<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<!-- This is a WordPress eXtended RSS file generated by WordPress as an export of your site. -->
<!-- It contains information about your site's posts, pages, comments, categories, and other content. -->
<!-- You may use this file to transfer that content from one site to another. -->
<!-- This file is not intended to serve as a complete backup of your site. -->

<!-- To import this information into a WordPress site follow these steps: -->
<!-- 1. Log in to that site as an administrator. -->
<!-- 2. Go to Tools: Import in the WordPress admin panel. -->
<!-- 3. Install the "WordPress" importer from the list. -->
<!-- 4. Activate & Run Importer. -->
<!-- 5. Upload this file using the form provided on that page. -->
<!-- 6. You will first be asked to map the authors in this export file to users -->
<!--    on the site. For each author, you may choose to map to an -->
<!--    existing user on the site or to create a new user. -->
<!-- 7. WordPress will then import each of the posts, pages, comments, categories, etc. -->
<!--    contained in this file into your site. -->

	
<rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:excerpt="http://wordpress.org/export/1.2/excerpt/"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:wp="http://wordpress.org/export/1.2/"
>

<channel>
	<title>Short and Sweet Review</title>
	<link>https://shortandsweet.wtf</link>
	<description>short, sweet, and occasionally strange since 7/4/2016</description>
	<pubDate>Thu, 19 Dec 2019 00:41:50 +0000</pubDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<wp:wxr_version>1.2</wp:wxr_version>
	<wp:base_site_url>https://shortandsweet.wtf</wp:base_site_url>
	<wp:base_blog_url>https://shortandsweet.wtf</wp:base_blog_url>

		<wp:author><wp:author_id>67389914</wp:author_id><wp:author_login><![CDATA[eegering]]></wp:author_login><wp:author_email><![CDATA[emilyegering@gmail.com]]></wp:author_email><wp:author_display_name><![CDATA[eegering]]></wp:author_display_name><wp:author_first_name><![CDATA[]]></wp:author_first_name><wp:author_last_name><![CDATA[]]></wp:author_last_name></wp:author>

				
	

<image>
	<url>https://shortandsweet.wtf/wp-content/uploads/2019/12/cropped-candylogoV3-32x32.png</url>
	<title>Short and Sweet Review</title>
	<link>https://shortandsweet.wtf</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">114070832</site>
		<item>
		<title>The Book of Thoth</title>
		<link>https://shortandsweet.wtf/story/the-book-of-thoth/</link>
		<pubDate>Sat, 10 Aug 2019 18:47:19 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[eegering]]></dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://shortandsweet.wtf/?post_type=story&#038;p=432</guid>
		<description></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>And thus it fell, that of all things on earth<br>My brother Nefrekepta most of worth<br>Did hold the wisdom that in Books is writ.<br>The tablets of the House of Death and Birth,</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>And all that on the temple walls is said.<br>And all the lore of the Kings' Tombs he read,<br>And ever walked in Memphis on the Hill<br>Of Kings, and stored the wisdom of the dead.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:more -->
<!--more-->
<!-- /wp:more -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Now one day was a high procession sent<br>To Ptah's great house; and Nefrekepta went<br>And walked therein; right slow he walked, and read<br>All that was writ on wall and pediment.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>And, watching him, behold, an aged Priest<br>Laughed. And he said: 'God's mercy be increased!<br>Why laughest thou at me?' And he: 'I laugh<br>At no man, not the greatest nor the least;</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>I laugh to think how thou shalt laugh anon,<br>When that which no man's eye hath looked upon,<br>The secret Book of Hermes which is Thoth,<br>Is opened to thine hand and called thine own.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>He wrote and the Gods before his face<br>Fled. —And it lies ... If ever word of grace<br>Or spell of power thou need, come then to me<br>And speak. Thou shalt be guided to the place.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Two leaves it hath, on which two sorceries<br>Are written. If thou read the first of these,<br>Thou shalt enchant the earth, the clouds above,<br>The underworld, the mountains and the seas;</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>And all the words that winged things may say.<br>And creeping things, shall be made thine that day;<br>Yea, thou shalt see all fishes in the deep<br>And God's power guiding each upon his way.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>And if thou read the second, though there lies<br>Above thee all Amenti, thou shalt rise<br>And take thy shape again, and see the Moon<br>And Ra and all the children of the skies.'</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>And Nefrekepta cried: 'O Priest and King!<br>I bless thee. Tell me every gorgeous thing<br>Thy soul desireth, they shall all be thine.<br>Wilt thou but guide my steps to that great spring.'</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Then smiled the Priest: 'My Prince, so let it be!<br>Send me an hundred bars of silver, free<br>Of all fault, for my burial when I die;<br>And two full priesthoods give me without fee.'</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>And Nefrekepta called a youth, and bade<br>An hundred bars of silver pure be made,<br>And two new priesthoods named to Thoth and Ptah,<br>And sealed him priest to Ptah and Thoth unpaid.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Then the man spoke: 'The Book of Thoth doth rest<br>In Coptos Sea, hid in a golden chest;<br>The gold doth lie in silver; that in wrought<br>Ebon and ivory, fitted nest in nest;</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>That in sweet cedar; that in bronze doth lie;<br>The bronze in iron. 'Tis knotted with a ply<br>Of endless Snake; and round it for one league<br>Are scorpion, asp, and worm to make men die.'</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>He spoke, and Nefrekepta no more knew<br>What place he stood in nor what breath he drew,<br>But forth he hied him in great joy, and caught<br>My hand, and all this tale he told me true;</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>And cried: 'South, South to Coptos! None shall stay<br>Our going.' But I turned from him away<br>And found that aged Priest and said: 'Thou Priest,<br>May Amun curse thee for thy words this day!</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>The Book of Thoth, the serpents and the sea!<br>Most bitter striving thou hast made for me.<br>And bitter watching till my lord's return;<br>False art thou, and thy South all cruelty.'</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>And much I prayed my brother not to sail<br>To Coptos, but my prayer might not avail.<br>For straight to Pharaoh's throne he went, and spake<br>To Pharaoh of the Priest and all his tale.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>And Pharaoh said: 'What wilt thou I should do?'<br>'Give me thy ship of pleasure and its crew,'<br>He said: 'and with me let Ahure sail<br>To find the Book, and the boy Merab too.'</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>So Pharaoh's pleasure-ship was brought, and all<br>Its crew; and southward in high festival<br>We sailed to Coptos; and the news went forth<br>Before us, and the folk stood on the wall.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>The Priests of Isis and Harpocrates<br>And the Chief Priest of Isis, all of these<br>Came down to Nefrekepta, and to me<br>The women of the Priests in their degrees.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>They led us to their Temple in a line;<br>And Nefrekepta gave ox, goose, and wine,<br>And brought to Isis and Harpocrates<br>Rite and oblation and all dues divine.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>A temple beautiful exceedingly<br>Was over us, and there four days did he<br>Make with the Priests of Isis holiday,<br>And the priests' women holiday with me.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>But when the morning of the fifth day came,<br>He called for wax made holy, without blame,<br>And shaped a boat with men, and spake a spell,<br>And breathed; and life woke in them like a flame.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>He went on board that boat, and heaped it high<br>With sand, and pushed it from the shore. And I<br>Sate on the shore alone, and said: 'I wait<br>Here till he comes, and if he dies I die.'</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>He said: 'O Rowers, row me to the place<br>I wot of.' And the rowers rowed apace,<br>By day, by night, and ceased on the third day.<br>Then he took sand, and cast the sand a space</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Before him, and the water rose on both<br>Sides, and the floor below did ooze and froth<br>With scorpion, asp, and worm to make men die,<br>One league before the treasure chest of Thoth.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>And round the chest was coiled an endless Snake.<br>Then Nefrekepta took his charms, and spake<br>A spell on all that league of serpent things.<br>And down they sank, and slept, and could not wake.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Then o'er the league of asps he walked, and fought<br>With the endless Snake and slew it; but it caught<br>Life as it fell, and joined again and flew<br>To tear him; and again its death he wrought;</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Then a third time it quickened, and again<br>He fought and smote the endless Snake in twain<br>The third time; and between the parts he cast<br>Fine sand; and it lay still, for ever slain.&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>And on he strode and found the caskets, rolled<br>Each within each; iron the outmost fold,<br>Then bronze; then cedar; then came ivory<br>And ebon; then the silver; then the gold.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>He broke the gold, and kneeling on his knees<br>Read out the first of the two sorceries.<br>Enchanting all the earth, the clouds above,<br>The underworld, the mountains and the seas.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>And everything that bird or worm might say,<br>Or mountain beast, he heard and knew that day,<br>And saw all fishes moving in the deep,<br>And God's power guiding each upon its way.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>He read the second sorcery, and far<br>In heaven he saw the shining forth of Ra,<br>And all his Children round him, and the Moon<br>Uprising, and the shape of every Star.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>And Nefrekepta shut the Book, and then<br>Went to his boat and called the magic men:<br>'Row day, row night, and row me to the shore.'<br>So rowed they, and he reached the shore again.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>And found me sitting by the sea to wait<br>His coming. Seven full days and nights I sate,<br>And ate nor drank, but waited, and was grown<br>Like them they bear to the embalmer's gate.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>I said to him:&nbsp; 'My brother, let me see<br>The Book that wrought such pain on thee and me.'<br>He gave the Book into my hands, and slow<br>I read what there was writ of sorcery.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>I laid upon the earth and sky my spell.<br>The underworld, the hills, the ocean swell;<br>And understood what tales the birds of heaven<br>And mountain beasts and deep-sea fishes tell.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Then did I read the second spell, and high<br>Above saw Ra enthroned in the sky,<br>And all his Children; and I saw the Moon<br>And all the Stars in all their shapes go by.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>And Nefrekepta bade them bring a roll<br>Of new papyrus, and wrote out the whole<br>Of those two charms, and melted it in wine,<br>And drank it. So the charm was in his soul.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Then sacrifice we made and gifts of worth<br>Heaped high in all the temples, and set forth<br>On Pharaoh's ship with singing and great joy,<br>One league, one league, from Coptos to the North.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>But Thoth himself had seen our deed, and, ah,<br>His wrath was hot! Before the throne of Ra,<br>'Judgement!' he cried, ;Give judgement between me<br>And Nefrekepta, son of Merneb-Ptah,</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Who broke into my treasure-house this day,<br>And slew my Snake and stole my Book away.'<br>And Ra said: 'Surely he is in thy hand,<br>O Thoth, both he and his, to spare or slay.'</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>And lo, a Power of God went forth, and fell<br>On all the river and lay invisible;<br>And Thoth said: 'Nefrekepta shall come home<br>No more, nor one of those that with him dwell.'</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Then the boy Merab, singing, from the shade<br>Of Pharaoh's awning stepped; one step he made,<br>And, lo, the River took him, and his face<br>Was covered and the will of Ra obeyed.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Then all about us cried with a great cry.<br>But Nefrekepta from his awning high<br>Called with a spell, and the dead boy rose up;<br>But over him that Power of God did lie.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Then Nefrekepta spake a written spell,<br>And the boy Merab told all that befell<br>About him; yea, the very words which Thoth<br>Spake at the throne of Ra he made him tell.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Then slow to Coptos we returned, and bore<br>The boy Merab to the embalmer's door;<br>And like a Prince he was embalmed and laid<br>On Coptos Hill with the great dead of yore.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>And Nefrekepta said: 'My sister, come<br>Quick; let us row till all the road be foam,<br>Lest Pharaoh hear what hath befallen us,<br>And his heart faint because we come not home.'</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>We went on board, and northward rowed apace<br>One league from Coptos; and I saw the place<br>Where Merab died, and from the canopy<br>Stepped, and the River took me; and my face</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Was covered and the will of Ra obeyed.<br>Then all upon the boat great mourning made,<br>But Nefrekepta from his awning high<br>Called, and I knew a spell upon me laid;</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>And I rose up, though o'er me still had hold<br>That Power of God. I rose and did unfold<br>All that befell me, yea, and every word<br>Which Thoth before Ra's throne had spoke I told.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Then slow to Coptos he returned and bore<br>Me, his dead sister, to the embalmer's door;<br>And like a Queen I was embalmed, and laid<br>Where Merab my dead child was laid before.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>He went on board, and down the stream apace<br>Rowed one league north from Coptos, to the place<br>Where Merab died and I, Ahure, died;<br>And stood and communed with his heart a space:</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>'Shall it be backward now, ere Thoth can slay?<br>Shall it be on to Pharaoh, come what may?<br>And, lo, when Pharaoh asks me where those two,<br>His children, are, what is it I shall say?</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>"I took thy children to a burning land<br>And living let them die; and here I stand."<br>I will not speak it.'—Then he bade them bring<br>A band of finest linen, such a band</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>As dead kings wear, to bind them at the last;<br>And seven times round his body made it fast,<br>And close against his body bound the Book<br>Firm; and from out the canopy he passed.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>And, lo, the River took him, and the will<br>Of Ra was done. And they on board did fill<br>The air with wailing: 'Great woe! Grievous woe!<br>Dead, dead, is the Good Scribe and all his skill.'</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>And down the stream the pleasure-ship sailed on<br>Toward Memphis, and to no man there was known<br>Where Nefrekepta lay; and when they came<br>Message was brought to Pharaoh on his throne.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>And Pharaoh came in robes of funeral,<br>And all the folk of Memphis, great and small.<br>And Ptah's High Priest and all the Priests of Ptah,<br>And Pharaoh's council and his household, all;</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>And saw the ship, and, lo, beneath it drowned<br>Saw Nefrekepta lying, both hands wound<br>About the rudder, guiding still his ship;<br>So great a scribe was Nefrekepta found.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>They raised him, and against his body dead<br>They found the Book pressed close. And Pharaoh said:<br>'Behold the Book he died for! Let it lie<br>In this King's grave, a pillow for his head.'</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Then sixteen days embalming did they keep<br>For Nefrekepta, thirty-five of deep<br>Wrapping; of burial threescore days and ten;<br>And here he resteth in the House of Sleep.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>And I, Ahure, far away must lie<br>In Coptos; but my heart within doth cry<br>For Nefrekepta, and our shadows come<br>Waking and watch beside him sleeplessly.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>432</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date><![CDATA[2019-08-10 14:47:19]]></wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt><![CDATA[2019-08-10 18:47:19]]></wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status><![CDATA[closed]]></wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status><![CDATA[closed]]></wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name><![CDATA[the-book-of-thoth]]></wp:post_name>
		<wp:status><![CDATA[publish]]></wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type><![CDATA[story]]></wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password><![CDATA[]]></wp:post_password>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
										<category domain="region" nicename="002"><![CDATA[Africa &amp; Egypt]]></category>
		<category domain="theme" nicename="confrontation-with-death"><![CDATA[confrontation with death]]></category>
		<category domain="author" nicename="gilbert-murray"><![CDATA[Gilbert Murray]]></category>
		<category domain="theme" nicename="human-brotherhood"><![CDATA[human brotherhood]]></category>
		<category domain="theme" nicename="the-mysterious-stranger"><![CDATA[the mysterious stranger]]></category>
		<category domain="theme" nicename="the-nature-of-evil"><![CDATA[the nature of evil]]></category>
		<category domain="demon" nicename="thoth"><![CDATA[Thoth]]></category>
						<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_edit_last]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[67389914]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							</item>
					<item>
		<title>Spirits—Good and Bad</title>
		<link>https://shortandsweet.wtf/story/spirits-good-and-bad/</link>
		<pubDate>Sat, 10 Aug 2019 19:27:26 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[eegering]]></dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://shortandsweet.wtf/?post_type=story&#038;p=436</guid>
		<description></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>All the tribes seemed to be thoroughly convinced of the existence of evil spirits.&nbsp; Of course, each will have its own name for the chief of these demons.  Otherwise there is not much difference.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:more -->
<!--more-->
<!-- /wp:more -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>The Dieyerie tribe call the Evil One "<em>Kootchie</em>."&nbsp; Nearly every case of sickness or death arising from apparently natural causes, is ascribed to Kootchie.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>When it thunders, it is <em>Kootchie growling</em>.&nbsp; If it thunders long and loud, the whole tribe will rush out, and, elevating their hands, they will cry out simultaneously, "<em>Hoo! Hoo!</em>" to frighten Kootchie away.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>If wild pigeons coo in the night, they are very much frightened and excited, for they are sure it is the Evil Spirit which occasions it.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Whirlwinds come, as they think, from the same source.&nbsp; Should a whirlwind approach the camp, they throw boomerangs at it.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>With some tribes this spirit is known as <em>Muuruup</em> (mooroop).&nbsp; He visits the earth in lightning.&nbsp; He it is who knocks down trees.  He is hated and feared.&nbsp; Owls are his agents.  When an owl hoots, the children creep under their rugs.&nbsp; He is not feared much in daylight, but greatly dreaded at night.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Mooroop lives under ground, where there is nothing but fire, and where bad people get no meat nor drink, but where they are terribly knocked about by the evil spirits.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Throughout Victoria this being is known as <em>Bunyip</em>.  He is very voracious in his appetite for human beings.  Its groanings and bellowings can be heard by all natives living near swamps or lagoons.  One day a woman fishing in a pond for eels caught them as fast as her husband could carry them to the camp.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>It turned out to be just as the husband feared, a trick on the part of the Bunyip to entice the woman to come and fish when her husband was not present, and so one day Bunyip swallowed her (as was supposed), for her husband never could find her.  In the Western Port region the Bunyip is known as <em>Too-roo-dun</em>.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>436</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date><![CDATA[2019-08-10 15:27:26]]></wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt><![CDATA[2019-08-10 19:27:26]]></wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status><![CDATA[closed]]></wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status><![CDATA[closed]]></wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name><![CDATA[spirits-good-and-bad]]></wp:post_name>
		<wp:status><![CDATA[publish]]></wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type><![CDATA[story]]></wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password><![CDATA[]]></wp:post_password>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
										<category domain="demon" nicename="bunyip"><![CDATA[Bunyip]]></category>
		<category domain="author" nicename="daniel-vannorman-lucas"><![CDATA[Daniel Vannorman Lucas]]></category>
		<category domain="region" nicename="009"><![CDATA[Oceania]]></category>
		<category domain="theme" nicename="the-nature-of-evil"><![CDATA[the nature of evil]]></category>
		<category domain="theme" nicename="woman-in-a-male-society"><![CDATA[woman in a male society]]></category>
						<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_edit_last]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[67389914]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							</item>
					<item>
		<title>How Milu became the King of Ghosts</title>
		<link>https://shortandsweet.wtf/story/how-milu-became-the-king-of-ghosts/</link>
		<pubDate>Mon, 12 Aug 2019 23:05:58 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[eegering]]></dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://shortandsweet.wtf/?post_type=story&#038;p=438</guid>
		<description></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Lono was a chief living on the western side of the island Hawaii. He had a very red skin and strange-looking eyes. His choice of occupation was farming. This man had never been sick. One time he was digging with the oo, a long sharp-pointed stick or spade. A man passed and admired him. The people said, "Lono has never been sick." The man said, " He will be sick."</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Lono was talking about that man and at the same time struck his oo down with force and cut his foot. He shed much blood, and fainted, falling to the ground. A man took a pig, went after the stranger, and let the pig go, which ran to this man. The stranger was Kamaka, a god of healing. He turned and went back at the call of the messenger, taking some popolo fruit and leaves in his cloak. When he came to the injured man he asked for salt, which he pounded into the fruit and leaves and placed in coco cloth and bound it on the wound, leaving it a long time. Then he went away.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:more -->
<p><!--more--></p>
<!-- /wp:more -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>As he journeyed on he heard heavy breathing, and turning saw Lono, who said, "You have helped me, and so I have left my lands in the care of my friends, directing them what to do, and have hastened after you to learn how to heal other people."</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>The god said, "Lono, open your mouth!" This Lono did, and the god spat in his mouth, so that the saliva could be taken into every part of Lono's body. Thus a part of the god became a part of Lono, and he became very skilful in the use of all healing remedies. He learned about the various diseases and the medicines needed for each. The god and Lono walked together, Lono receiving new lessons along the way, passing through the districts of Kau, Puna, Hilo, and then to Hamakua.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>The god said, "It is not right for us to stay together. You can never accomplish anything by staying with me. You must go to a separate place and give yourself up to healing people."</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Lono turned aside to dwell in Waimanu and Waipio Valleys and there began to practise healing, becoming very noted, while the Kamaka made his home at Ku-kui-haele.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>This god did not tell the other gods of the medicines that he had taught Lono. One of the other gods, Kalae, was trying to find some way to kill Milu, and was always making him sick. Milu, chief of Waipio, heard of the skill of Lono. Some had been sick even to death, and Lono had healed them. Therefore Milu sent a messenger to Lono who responded at once, came and slapped Milu all over the body, and said: "You are not ill. Obey me and you shall be well."</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Then he healed him from all the sickness inside the body caused by Kalae. But there was danger from outside, so he said: "You must build a ti-leaf house and dwell there quietly for some time, letting your disease rest. If a company should come by the house making sport, with a great noise, do not go out, because when you go they will come up and get you for your death. Do not open the ti leaves and look out. The day you do this you shall die."</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Some time passed and the chief remained in the house, but one day there was the confused noise of many people talking and shouting around his house. He did not forget the command of Lono. Two birds were sporting in a wonderful way in the sky above the forest. This continued all day until it was dark.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Then another long time passed and again Waipio was full of resounding noises. A great bird appeared in the sky resplendent in all kinds of feathers, swaying from side to side over the valley, from the top of one precipice across to the top of another, in grand flights passing over the heads of the people, who shouted until the valley re-echoed with the sound.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Milu became tired of that great noise and could not patiently obey his physician, so he pushed aside some of the ti leaves of his house and looked out upon the bird. That was the time when the bird swept down upon the house, thrusting a claw under Milu's arm, tearing out his liver. Lono saw this and ran after the bird, but it flew swiftly to a deep pit in the lava on one side of the valley and dashed inside, leaving blood spread on the stones. Lono came, saw the blood, took it and wrapped it in a piece of tapa cloth and returned to the place where the chief lay almost dead. He poured some medicine into the wound and pushed the tapa and blood inside. Milu was soon healed.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>The place where the bird hid with the liver of Milu is called to this day Ke-ake-o-Milu ("The liver of Milu"). When this death had passed away he felt very well, even as before his trouble. Then Lono told him that another death threatened him and would soon appear. He must dwell in quietness.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>For some time Milu was living in peace and quiet after this trouble. Then one day the surf of Waipio became very high, rushing from far out even to the sand, and the people entered into the sport of surf-riding with great joy and loud shouts. This noise continued day by day, and Milu was impatient of the restraint and forgot the words of Lono. He went out to bathe in the surf.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>When he came to the place of the wonderful surf he let the first and second waves go by, and as the third came near he launched himself upon it while the people along the beach shouted uproariously. He went out again into deeper water, and again came in, letting the first and second waves go first. As he came to the shore the first and second waves were hurled back from the shore in a great mass against the wave upon which he was riding. The two great masses of water struck and pounded Milu, whirling and crowding him down, while the surfboard was caught in the raging, struggling waters and thrown out toward the shore. Milu was completely lost in the deep water.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>The people cried: "Milu is dead! The chief is dead!" The god Kalae thought he had killed Milu, so he with the other poison-gods went on a journey to Mauna Loa. Kapo and Pua, the poison-gods, or gods of death, of the island Maui, found them as they passed, and joined the company. They discovered a forest on Molokai, and there as kupua spirits, or ghost bodies, entered into the trees of that forest, so the trees became the kupua bodies. They were the medicinal or poison qualities in the trees.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Lono remained in Waipio Valley, becoming the ancestor and teacher of all the good healing priests of Hawaii, but Milu became the ruler of the Underworld, the place where the spirits of the dead had their home after they were driven away from the land of the living. Many people came to him from time to time.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>He established ghostly sports like those which his subjects had enjoyed before death. They played the game kilu with polished cocoanut shells, spinning them over a smooth surface to strike a post set up in the centre. He taught konane, a game commonly called "Hawaiian checkers," but more like the Japanese game of "Go." He permitted them to gamble, betting all the kinds of property found in ghost-land. They boxed and wrestled; they leaped from precipices into ghostly swimming-pools; they feasted and fought, sometimes attempting to slay each other. Thus they lived the ghost life as they had lived on earth. Sometimes the ruler was forgotten and the ancient Hawaiians called the Underworld by his name Milu. The New Zealanders "frequently gave their Underworld the name Miru." They also supposed that the ghosts feasted and sported as they had done while living.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>438</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date><![CDATA[2019-08-12 19:05:58]]></wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt><![CDATA[2019-08-12 23:05:58]]></wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status><![CDATA[closed]]></wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status><![CDATA[closed]]></wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name><![CDATA[how-milu-became-the-king-of-ghosts]]></wp:post_name>
		<wp:status><![CDATA[publish]]></wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type><![CDATA[story]]></wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password><![CDATA[]]></wp:post_password>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
										<category domain="region" nicename="019"><![CDATA[Americas]]></category>
		<category domain="theme" nicename="confrontation-with-death"><![CDATA[confrontation with death]]></category>
		<category domain="theme" nicename="initiation"><![CDATA[initiation]]></category>
		<category domain="demon" nicename="milu"><![CDATA[Milu]]></category>
		<category domain="author" nicename="william-drake-westervelt"><![CDATA[William Drake Westervelt]]></category>
						<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_edit_last]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[67389914]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[story-author]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[William Drake Westervelt]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[death-god-demon]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[Milu]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[rregion]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[Americas]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[themes]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[Confrontation with death, initiation]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							</item>
					<item>
		<title>The Thirty-Three Places</title>
		<link>https://shortandsweet.wtf/story/the-thirty-three-places/</link>
		<pubDate>Mon, 12 Aug 2019 23:08:26 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[eegering]]></dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://shortandsweet.wtf/?post_type=story&#038;p=440</guid>
		<description></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>The "Thirty-three Places"—Jap. Saikoku San-ju-san Sho—are thirty-three shrines sacred to Kwannon, the Goddess of Mercy, in the provinces near Kyoto.  They are all carefully numbered, the first being Fudaraku-ji at Nachi in Kishu, and the last Tanigumi-dera in Mino.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Legend traces the institution of these "Thirty-three Places" to Tokudo Shonin, a famous Buddhist abbot of the 8th century.  This holy man, having suddenly died, was received by two emissaries of Emma-O, the God or Regent of the Underworld, and conducted to the latter's iron castle that glitters with gold and silver and with pearls and every kind of precious stones.  The god, himself resplendent as a jewel and beaming with smiles, received the dead abbot with distinguished attention, and forthwith revealed to him the existence of Three-and-thirty Places specially cared for by the Goddess of Mercy, Saviour of the World (Guse Kwan-ze-on), who had thus divided herself into many bodies, wishing to succour each human being in the way best suited to his particular spiritual antecedents.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:more -->
<!--more-->
<!-- /wp:more -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>But alas! none yet knew of the existence of these shrines; so men went on doing evil rather than good, and kept falling into hell as plentifully as the raindrops fall in a furious summer shower, whereas a single pilgrimage to the Three-and-thirty Places would cause the pilgrim to radiate light from the soles of his feet, and give him strength to crush all the one hundred and thirty-six hells into fragments.  "Should, peradventure, anyone that has accomplished the pilgrimage fall into hell," said Emma-O, "I, myself, will exchange with him, and suffer in his stead, as a teller of false tales.  Here, therefore, is a list of the Three-and-thirty Places.  Carry it back to the world of the living, and do the needful in the matter.  It was for this purpose that I sent for thee hither."  Tokudo thanked the Regent of the Underworld for his kindness, but remarked that mortals had grown sceptical in these latter days, and would ask for a sign to accredit his embassage.  Thereupon Emma-O gave him his own jewelled seal, and the abbot was led back by the same two attendants as before to the sinful world.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Now what had happened there was, that though he had lain as dead for three days and three nights, his body had not grown cold.&nbsp; His disciples therefore had refrained from burying him, thinking that he might possibly be restored to life.  When he did awake from the trance, there, grasped in his right hand, was the seal which the Regent of the Underworld had given him.&nbsp; Then he told his disciples all that had happened, and he and they started off on a round of the Three-and-thirty Places, as the first pilgrims to those holy shrines; and as the oldest temple in Japan dedicated to the Merciful Goddess was that of Nakayama-dera in Settsu, which the Prince Shotoku Taishi had built, they visited that first.&nbsp; There also did he leave the jewelled seal in a stone casket.<br></p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>440</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date><![CDATA[2019-08-12 19:08:26]]></wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt><![CDATA[2019-08-12 23:08:26]]></wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status><![CDATA[closed]]></wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status><![CDATA[closed]]></wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name><![CDATA[the-thirty-three-places]]></wp:post_name>
		<wp:status><![CDATA[publish]]></wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type><![CDATA[story]]></wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password><![CDATA[]]></wp:post_password>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
										<category domain="region" nicename="asia"><![CDATA[Asia]]></category>
		<category domain="theme" nicename="confrontation-with-death"><![CDATA[confrontation with death]]></category>
		<category domain="region" nicename="030"><![CDATA[Eastern Asia]]></category>
		<category domain="demon" nicename="emma-o"><![CDATA[Emma-O]]></category>
		<category domain="author" nicename="john-murray"><![CDATA[John Murray]]></category>
						<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_edit_last]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[67389914]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							</item>
					<item>
		<title>Schamir</title>
		<link>https://shortandsweet.wtf/story/schamir/</link>
		<pubDate>Mon, 12 Aug 2019 23:12:45 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[eegering]]></dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://shortandsweet.wtf/?post_type=story&#038;p=442</guid>
		<description></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>As Solomon, thus ran the tale, was about to build the temple without the use of iron, his wise men drew his attention to the stones of the high priest's breastplate, which had been cut and polished by something harder than themselves. This was schamir, which was able to cut where iron would not bite.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Thereupon Solomon summoned the spirits to inform him of the whereabouts of this substance. They told him schamir was a worm of the size of a barley corn, but so powerful that the hardest flint could not resist him. The spirits advised Solomon to seek Asmodeus, king of the devils, who could give him further information.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:more -->
<!--more-->
<!-- /wp:more -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>When Solomon inquired where Asmodeus was to be met with, they replied that, on a distant mountain, he had dug a huge cistern, out of which he daily drank. Solomon then sent Benaiah with a chain, on which was written the magic word "schem hammphorasch," a fleece of wool and a skin of wine. Benaiah, having arrived at the cistern of Asmodeus, undermined it and let the water off by a little hole, which he then plugged up with the wool; after which he filled the pit with wine. The evil spirit came, as was his wont, to the cistern, and scented the wine.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Suspecting treachery, he refused to drink, and retired; but at length, impelled by thirst, he drank, and, becoming intoxicated, was chained by Benaiah and carried away. Benaiah had no willing prisoner to conduct: Asmodeus plunged and kicked, upsetting trees and houses. In this manner he came near hut in which lived a widow, and when she besought him not to injure her poor little cot, he turned aside, and, in so doing, broke his leg. " Rightly," said the devil, "is it written 'a soft tongue breaketh the bone!'" (Prov. XXV. 15). And a <em>diable boiteux</em> he has ever remained.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>When in the presence of Solomon, Asmodeus was constrained to behave with greater decorum. Schamir, he told Solomon, was the property of the Prince of the Sea, and that prince entrusted none with the mysterious worm except the moor-hen, which had taken an oath of fidelity to him. The moor-hen takes the schamir with her to the tops of the mountains, splits them, and injects seeds, which grow and cover the naked rocks. Wherefore the bird is called Naggar Tura, the mountain-carver. If Solomon desired to possess himself of the worm, he must find the nest of the moor-hen, and cover it with a plate of glass, so that the mother bird could not get at her young without breaking the glass. She would seek schamir for the purpose, and the worm must be obtained from her.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Accordingly, Benaiah, son of Jehoiada, sought the nest of the bird, and laid over it a piece of glass. When the moor-hen came, and could not reach her young, she flew away and fetched schamir, and placed it on the glass. Then Benaiah shouted, and so terrified the bird, that she dropped the worm and flew away. Benaiah by this means obtained possession of the coveted schamir, and bore it to Solomon. But the moor-hen was so distressed at having broken her oath to the Prince of the Sea that she slew herself.<br></p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>According to another version, Solomon went to his fountain, where he found the demon Sackar, whom he captured by a ruse, and chained down. Solomon pressed his ring to the chains, and Sackar uttered a cry so shrill that the earth quaked.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Quoth Solomon, "Fear not; I shall restore you to liberty if you will tell me how to burrow noiselessly after minerals and metals."</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>"I know not how to do so," answered the Jin; "but the raven can tell you: place over her eggs a sheet of crystal, and you shall see how the mother will break it."</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Solomon did so, and the mother brought a stone and shattered the crystal. " Whence got you that stone?'" asked Solomon.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>"It is the stone Samur," answered the raven; "it comes from a desert in the uttermost east." So the monarch sent some giants to follow the raven, and bring him a suitable number of stones."</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>According to a third version, the bird is an eagle, and schamir is the Stone of Wisdom.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Possessed of this schamir, Solomon wrought the stones for his temple.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>442</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date><![CDATA[2019-08-12 19:12:45]]></wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt><![CDATA[2019-08-12 23:12:45]]></wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status><![CDATA[closed]]></wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status><![CDATA[closed]]></wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name><![CDATA[schamir]]></wp:post_name>
		<wp:status><![CDATA[publish]]></wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type><![CDATA[story]]></wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password><![CDATA[]]></wp:post_password>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
										<category domain="region" nicename="asia"><![CDATA[Asia]]></category>
		<category domain="demon" nicename="asmodeus"><![CDATA[Asmodeus]]></category>
		<category domain="author" nicename="sabine-baring-gould"><![CDATA[Sabine Baring-Gould]]></category>
		<category domain="region" nicename="034"><![CDATA[Southern Asia]]></category>
		<category domain="theme" nicename="triumph-by-trickery"><![CDATA[triumph by trickery]]></category>
						<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_edit_last]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[67389914]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							</item>
					<item>
		<title>How the Camel Got His Hump</title>
		<link>https://shortandsweet.wtf/story/how-the-camel-got-his-hump/</link>
		<pubDate>Tue, 13 Aug 2019 21:17:45 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[eegering]]></dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://shortandsweet.wtf/?post_type=story&#038;p=466</guid>
		<description></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p><img class="aligncenter wp-image-445 size-thumbnail" src="https://shortandsweet.wtf/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/camel-150x150.png" alt="" width="150" height="150" /></p>
<p>Now this is the next tale, and it tells how the Camel got his big hump.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>In the beginning of years, when the world was so new and all, and the Animals were just beginning to work for Man, there was a Camel, and he lived in the middle of a Howling Desert because he did not want to work; and besides, he was a Howler himself. So he ate sticks and thorns and tamarisks and milkweed and prickles, most 'scruciating idle; and when anybody spoke to him he said "Humph!" Just "Humph!" and no more.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:more -->
<p><!--more--></p>
<!-- /wp:more -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Presently the Horse came to him on Monday morning, with a saddle on his back and a bit in his mouth, and said, "Camel, O Camel, come out and trot like the rest of us."</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>"Humph!" said the Camel and the Horse went away and told the Man.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Presently the Dog came to him, with a stick in his mouth, and said, "Camel, O Camel, come and fetch and carry like the rest of us."</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>"Humph!" said the Camel; and the Dog went away and told the Man.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Presently the Ox came to him, with the yoke on his neck and said, "Camel, O Camel, come and plough like the rest of us."</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>"Humph!" said the Camel; and the Ox went away and told the Man.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>At the end of the day the Man called the Horse and the Dog and the Ox together, and said, "Three, O Three, I'm very sorry for you (with the world so new-and-all); but that Humph-thing in the Desert can't work, or he would have been here by now, so I am going to leave him alone, and you must work double-time to make up for it."</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>That made the Three very angry (with the world so new-and-all), and they held a palaver, and an indaba, and a punchayet, and a pow-wow on the edge of the Desert; and the Camel came chewing milkweed most 'scruciating idle, and laughed at them. Then he said "Humph!" and went away again.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Presently there came along the Djinn in charge of All Deserts, rolling in a cloud of dust (Djinns always travel that way because it is Magic), and he stopped to palaver and pow-wow with the Three.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>"Djinn of All Deserts," said the Horse, "is it right for any one to be idle, with the world so new-and-all?"</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>"Certainly not," said the Djinn.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>"Well," said the Horse, "there's a thing in the middle of your Howling Desert (and he's a Howler himself) with a long neck and long legs, and he hasn't done a stroke of work since Monday morning. He won't trot."</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>"Whew!" said the Djinn, whistling, "that's my Camel, for all the gold in Arabia! What does he say about it?"</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>"He says 'Humph!'" said the Dog; "and he won't fetch and carry."</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>"Does he say anything else?"</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>"Only 'Humph!'; and he won't plough," said the Ox.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>"Very good," said the Djinn. "I'll humph him if you will kindly wait a minute."</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>The Djinn rolled himself up in his dust-cloak, and took a bearing across the desert, and found the Camel most 'scruciatingly idle, looking at his own reflection in a pool of water.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>"My long and bubbling friend," said the Djinn, "what's this I hear of your doing no work, with the world so new-and-all?"</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>"Humph!" said the Camel.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>The Djinn sat down, with his chin in his hand, and began to think a Great Magic, while the Camel looked at his own reflection in the pool of water.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>"You've given the Three extra work ever since Monday morning, all on account of your 'scruciating idleness," said the Djinn; and he went on thinking Magics, with his chin in his hand.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>"Humph!" said the Camel.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>"I should n't say that again if I were you," said the Djinn; "you might say it once too often. Bubbles, I want you to work."</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>And the Camel said "Humph!" again; but no sooner had he said it than he saw his back, that he was so proud of, puffing up and puffing up into a great big lolloping humph.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>"Do you see that?" said the Djinn. "That's your very own humph that you've brought upon your very own self by not working. To-day is Thursday, and you've done no work since Monday, when the work began. Now you are going to work."</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>"How can I," said the Camel, "with this humph on my back?"</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>"That's made a-purpose," said the Djinn, "all because you missed those three days. You will be able to work now for three days without eating, because you can live on your humph; and don't you ever say I never did anything for you. Come out of the Desert and go to the Three, and behave. Humph yourself!"</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>And the Camel humphed himself, humph and all, and went away to join the Three. And from that day to this the Camel always wears a humph (we call it "hump" now, not to hurt his feelings); but he has never yet caught up with the three days that he missed at the beginning of the world, and he has never yet learned how to behave.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>466</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date><![CDATA[2019-08-13 17:17:45]]></wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt><![CDATA[2019-08-13 21:17:45]]></wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status><![CDATA[closed]]></wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status><![CDATA[closed]]></wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name><![CDATA[how-the-camel-got-his-hump]]></wp:post_name>
		<wp:status><![CDATA[publish]]></wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type><![CDATA[story]]></wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password><![CDATA[]]></wp:post_password>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
										<category domain="region" nicename="asia"><![CDATA[Asia]]></category>
		<category domain="demon" nicename="djinn"><![CDATA[Djinn]]></category>
		<category domain="theme" nicename="poetic-justice"><![CDATA[poetic justice]]></category>
		<category domain="author" nicename="rudyard-kipling"><![CDATA[Rudyard Kipling]]></category>
		<category domain="region" nicename="035"><![CDATA[South-Eastern Asia]]></category>
						<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_edit_last]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[67389914]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							</item>
					<item>
		<title>Odyssey XXIV</title>
		<link>https://shortandsweet.wtf/story/odyssey-xxiv/</link>
		<pubDate>Tue, 13 Aug 2019 21:45:16 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[eegering]]></dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://shortandsweet.wtf/?post_type=story&#038;p=468</guid>
		<description></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Now Cyllenian Hermes called forth from the halls the souls of the wooers, and he held in his hand his wand that is fair and golden, wherewith he lulls the eyes of men, of whomso he will, while others again he even wakens out of sleep. Herewith he roused and led the souls who followed gibbering.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>And even as bats flit gibbering in the secret place of a wondrous cave, when one has fallen down from the cluster on the rock, where they cling each to each up aloft, even so the souls gibbered as they fared together, and Hermes, the helper, led them down the dank ways.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:more -->
<!--more-->
<!-- /wp:more -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Past the streams of Oceanus and the White Rock, past the gates of the Sun they sped and the land of dreams, and soon they came to the mead of asphodel, where dwell the souls, the phantoms of men outworn. There they found the soul of Achilles, son of Peleus, and the souls of Patroclus, and of noble Antilochus, and of Aias, who in face and form was goodliest of all the Danaans after the noble son of Peleus.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>So these were flocking round Achilles, and the spirit of Agamemnon, son of Atreus, drew nigh sorrowful; and about him were gathered all the other shades, as many as perished with him in the house of Aegisthus, and met their doom. Now the soul of the son of Peleus spake to him first, saying:</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>'Son of Atreus, verily we deemed that thou above all other heroes wast evermore dear to Zeus, whose joy is in the thunder, seeing that thou wast lord over warriors, many and mighty men, in the land of the Trojans where we Achaeans suffered affliction. But lo, thee too was deadly doom to visit early, the doom that none avoids of all men born. Ah, would that in the fulness of thy princely honour, thou hadst met death and fate in the land of the Trojans! So would all the Achaean host have builded thee a barrow, yea and for thy son thou wouldst have won great glory in the aftertime. But now it has been decreed for thee to perish by a most pitiful death.' Then the soul of the son of Atreus answered, and spake: 'Happy art thou son of Peleus, godlike Achilles, that didst die in Troy-land far from Argos, and about thee fell others, the best of the sons of Trojans and Achaeans, fighting for thy body; but thou in the whirl of dust layest mighty and mightily fallen, forgetful of thy chivalry. And we strove the livelong day, nor would we ever have ceased from the fight, if Zeus had not stayed us with a tempest. Anon when we had borne thee to the ships from out of the battle, we laid thee on a bier and washed thy fair flesh clean with warm water and unguents, and around thee the Danaans shed many a hot tear and shore their hair. And forth from the sea came thy mother with the deathless maidens of the waters, when they heard the tidings; and a wonderful wailing rose over the deep, and trembling fell on the limbs of all the Achaeans. Yea, and they would have sprung up and departed to the hollow ships, had not one held them back that knew much lore from of old, Nestor, whose counsel proved heretofore the best. Out of his good-will he made harangue, and spake among them:</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>'"Hold, ye Argives, flee not, young lords of the Achaeans. Lo, his mother from the sea is she that comes, with the deathless maidens of the waters, to behold the face of her dead son.''</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>'So he spake, and the high-hearted Achaeans ceased from their flight. Then round thee stood the daughters of the ancient one of the sea, holding a pitiful lament, and they clad thee about in raiment incorruptible. And all the nine Muses one to the other replying with sweet voices began the dirge; there thou wouldest not have seen an Argive but wept, so mightily rose up the clear chant.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Thus for seventeen days and nights continually did we all bewail thee, immortal gods and mortal men. On the eighteenth day we gave thy body to the flames, and many well-fatted sheep we slew around thee, and kine of shambling gait. So thou wert burned in the garments of the gods, and in much unguents and in sweet honey, and many heroes of the Achaeans moved mail-clad around the pyre when thou wast burning, both footmen and horse, and great was the noise that arose.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>But when the flame of Hephaestus had utterly abolished thee, lo, in the morning we gathered together thy white bones, Achilles, and bestowed them in unmixed wine and in unguents. Thy mother gave a twy-handled golden urn, and said that it was the gift of Dionysus, and the workmanship of renowned Hephaestus. Therein lie great Achilles, and mingled therewith the bones of Patroclus, son of Menoetias, that is dead, but apart is the dust of Antilochus, whom thou didst honour above all thy other companions, after Patroclus that was dead.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Then over them did we pile a great and goodly tomb, we the holy host of Argive warriors, high on a jutting headland over wide Hellespont, that it might be far seen from off the sea by men that now are, and by those that shall be hereafter. Then thy mother asked the gods for glorious prizes in the games, and set them in the midst of the lists for the champions of the Achaeans. In days past thou hast been at the funeral games of many a hero, whenso, after some king's death, the young men gird themselves and make them ready for the meed of victory, but couldst thou have seen these gifts thou wouldst most have marvelled in spirit, such glorious prizes did the goddess set there to honour thee, even Thetis, the silver-footed; for very dear wert thou to the gods. Thus not even in death hast thou lost thy name, but to thee shall be a fair renown for ever among all men, Achilles. But what joy have I now herein, that I have wound up the clew of war, for on my return Zeus devised for me an evil end at the hands of Aegisthus and my wife accursed?'</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>So they spake one to the other. And nigh them came the Messenger, the slayer of Argos, leading down the ghosts of the wooers by Odysseus slain, and the two heroes were amazed at the sight and went straight toward them. And the soul of Agamemnon, son of Atreus, knew the dear son of Melaneus, renowned Amphimedon, who had been his host, having his dwelling in Ithaca. The soul of the son of Atreus spake to him first, saying:</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>'Amphimedon, what hath befallen you, that ye have come beneath the darkness of earth, all of you picked men and of like age? it is even as though one should choose out and gather together the best warriors in a city. Did Poseidon smite you in your ships and rouse up contrary winds and the long waves? Or did unfriendly men, perchance, do you hurt upon the land as ye were cutting off their oxen and fair flocks of sheep, or while they fought to defend their city and the women thereof? Answer and tell me, for I avow me a friend of thy house. Rememberest thou not the day when I came to your house in Ithaca with godlike Menelaus, to urge Odysseus to follow with me to Ilios on the decked ships? And it was a full month ere we had sailed all across the wide sea, for scarce could we win to our cause Odysseus, waster of cities.'</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Then the ghost of Amphimedon answered him, and spake: 'Most famous son of Atreus, king of men, Agamemnon, I remember all these things, O fosterling of Zeus, as thou declarest them, and I in turn will tell thee all the tale well and truly, even our death and evil end, on what wise it befell. We wooed the wife of Odysseus that was long afar, and she neither refused the hated bridal nor was minded to make an end, devising for us death and black fate. Also this other wile she contrived in her heart. She set up in her halls a mighty web, fine of woof and very wide, whereat she would weave, and anon she spake among us:</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>'"Ye princely youths, my wooers, now that goodly Odysseus is dead, do ye abide patiently, how eager soever to speed on this marriage of mine, till I finish the robe. I would not that the threads perish to no avail, even this shroud for the hero Laertes, against the day when the ruinous doom shall bring him low, of death that lays men at their length. So shall none of the Achaean women in the land count it blame in me; as well might be; were he to lie without a winding-sheet, a man that had gotten great possessions."</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>'So spake she, and our high hearts consented thereto. So then in the daytime she would weave the mighty web, and in the night unravel the same, when she had let place the torches by her. Thus for the space of three years she hid the thing by guile and won the minds of the Achaeans; but when the fourth year arrived and the seasons came round, as the months waned and many days were accomplished, then it was that one of her women who knew all declared it, and we found her unravelling the splendid web. Thus she finished perforce and sore against her will.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Now when she brought the robe to light, after she had woven the great web and washed and shone even as sun or moon, at that very hour some evil god led Odysseus, I know not whence, to the upland farm, where the swineherd abode in his dwelling. Thither too came the dear son of divine Odysseus out of sandy Pylos, voyaging with his black ship. These twain framed an evil death for the wooers, and came to the renowned town. Odysseus verily came the later, and Telemachus went before and led the way.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Now the swineherd brought Odysseus clad in vile raiment, in the likeness of beggar, a wretched man and an old, leaning on a staff, and behold, he was clad about in sorry raiment. And none of us, not even the elders, could know him for that he was, on this his sudden appearing, but with evil words we assailed him and hurled things at him. Yet for while he hardened his heart to endure both the hurlings and the evil words in his own halls; but at the last, when the spirit of Zeus, lord of the aegis, aroused him, by the help of Telemachus he took up all the goodly weapons, and laid them by in the inner chamber and drew the bolts.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Next in his great craft he bade his wife to offer his bow and store of grey iron to the wooers to be the weapons of our contest, luckless that we were, and the beginning of death. Now not one of us could stretch the string of the strong bow; far short we fell of that might. But when the great bow came to the hands of Odysseus, then we all clamoured and forbade to give him the bow, how much soever he might speak, but Telemachus alone was instant with him and commanded him to take it.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Then he took the bow into his hands, the steadfast goodly Odysseus, and lightly he strung and sent the arrow through the iron.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Then straight he went to the threshold and there took his stand, and poured forth the swift arrows, glancing terribly around, and smote the king Antinous. Thereafter on the others he let fly his bolts, winged for death, with straight aim, and the wooers fell thick one upon another. Then was it known how that some god was their helper, for pressing on as their passion drave them, they slew the men right and left through the halls, and thence there arose a hideous moaning, as heads were smitten and the floor all ran with blood.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>So we perished, Agamemnon, and even now our bodies lie uncared for in the halls of Odysseus, for the friends of each one at home as yet know nought, even they who might wash the black-clotted blood out of our wounds, and lay out the bodies and wail the dirge, for that is the due of the dead.'</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Then the ghost of the son of Atreus answered him: 'Ah, happy son of Laertes, Odysseus of many devices, yea, for a wife most excellent hast thou gotten, so good was the wisdom of constant Penelope, daughter of Icarius, that was duly mindful of Odysseus, her wedded lord. Wherefore the fame of her virtue shall never perish, but the immortals will make a gracious song in the ears of men on earth to the fame of constant Penelope. In far other wise did the daughter of Tyndareus devise ill deeds, and slay her wedded lord, and hateful shall the song of her be among men, and an evil repute hath she brought upon all womankind, even on the upright.'</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Even so these twain spake one to the other, standing in the house of Hades, beneath the secret places of the earth.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>468</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date><![CDATA[2019-08-13 17:45:16]]></wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt><![CDATA[2019-08-13 21:45:16]]></wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status><![CDATA[closed]]></wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status><![CDATA[closed]]></wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name><![CDATA[odyssey-xxiv]]></wp:post_name>
		<wp:status><![CDATA[publish]]></wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type><![CDATA[story]]></wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password><![CDATA[]]></wp:post_password>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
										<category domain="theme" nicename="confrontation-with-death"><![CDATA[confrontation with death]]></category>
		<category domain="demon" nicename="hermes"><![CDATA[Hermes]]></category>
		<category domain="demon" nicename="hermes-psychopompos"><![CDATA[Hermes Psychopompos]]></category>
		<category domain="author" nicename="homer"><![CDATA[Homer]]></category>
		<category domain="theme" nicename="poetic-justice"><![CDATA[poetic justice]]></category>
		<category domain="region" nicename="039"><![CDATA[Southern Europe]]></category>
		<category domain="theme" nicename="woman-in-a-male-society"><![CDATA[woman in a male society]]></category>
						<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_edit_last]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[67389914]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							</item>
					<item>
		<title>The Descent of Ishtar Into Hades</title>
		<link>https://shortandsweet.wtf/story/the-descent-of-ishtar-into-hades/</link>
		<pubDate>Tue, 13 Aug 2019 22:10:33 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[eegering]]></dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://shortandsweet.wtf/?post_type=story&#038;p=470</guid>
		<description></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Ereshkigal, referred to as Ninkigal in this translation, is the goddess of death in Mesopotamian, Sumerian and Babylonian mythology.  She rules over the underworld Aralu (also known as Arali, Ekur, Ganzir, Irkalla, Kigal, Kur, Kurnugia, Kutu, and Shalu).  Ereshkigal's messenger is Namtar, referred to as Simtar in this translation, who brings death by spreading disease.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:more -->
<!--more-->
<!-- /wp:more -->

<!-- wp:list {"ordered":true} -->
<ol><li>To Hades the land of . . . .</li><li>Ishtar daughter of Sin (the moon) her ear inclined;</li><li>inclined also the daughter of Sin her ear,</li><li>to the house of darkness the dwelling of the god Irkalla,</li><li>to the house entering which there is no exit,</li><li>to the road the course of which never returns,</li><li>to the house which on entering it they long for light,</li><li>the place where dust is their nourishment and their food mud.</li><li>Light is never seen in darkness they dwell,</li><li>its chiefs also are like birds covered with feathers,</li><li>over the door and bolts is scattered dust.</li><li>Ishtar on her arrival at the gate of Hades,</li><li>to the keeper of the gate a command she called:</li><li>Keeper of the waters open thy gate,</li><li>open thy gate that I may enter.</li><li>If thou openest not the gate and I am not admitted;</li><li>I will strike the door and the door posts I will shatter,</li><li>I will strike the hinges and I will burst open the doors;</li><li>I will raise up the dead devourers of the living,</li><li>over the living the dead shall triumph.</li><li>The keeper his mouth opened and spake,</li><li>and called to the princess Ishtar:</li><li>Stay lady do not do this,</li><li>let me go and thy speech repeat to the queen Ninkigal.</li><li>The keeper entered and called to Ninkigal:</li><li>this water they sister Ishtar . . . .</li><li>. . . . of the great vaults . . . .</li><li>Ninkigal on her hearing this</li><li>like the cutting off of . . . .</li><li>like the bit of an insect it . . . .</li><li>Will her heart support it, will her spirit uphold it;</li><li>this water I with . . . .</li><li>like food eaten like jugs of water drank . . .</li><li>Let her mourn for the husbands who forsake their wives.</li><li>Let her mourn for the wives who from the bosom of their husbands depart.</li><li>for the children who miscarry let her mourn, who are not born in their proper time.</li><li>Go keeper open thy gate</li><li>and enclose her like former visitors.</li><li>The keeper went and opened his gate,</li><li>on entering lady may the city of Cutha be . .</li><li>the palace of Hades is rejoicing at thy presence.</li><li>The first gate he passed her through and drew her in, and he took away the great crown of her head. .</li><li>Why keeper has thou taken away the great crown of my head.</li><li>On Entering lady, the goddess of the lower regions does thus with her visitors.</li><li>The second gate he passed her through and drew her in, and he took away the earrings of her ears.</li><li>Why keeper hast thou taken away the earrings of my ears.</li><li>On entering Lady, the goddess of the lower regions does thus with her visitors.</li><li>The third gate he passed her through and drew her in, and he took away the necklace of her neck.</li><li>Why keeper hast thou taken away the necklace of my neck.</li><li>On entering Lady, the goddess of the lower regions does thus with her visitors.</li><li>The fourth gate he passed her through and drew her in, and he took away the ornaments of her breast.</li><li>Why keeper hast thou taken away the ornaments of my breast.</li><li>On entering Lady, the goddess of the lower regions does thus with her visitors.</li><li>The fifth gate he passed her through and drew her in, and he took away the binding girdle of her waist.</li><li>Why keeper hast thou taken away the binding girdle of my waist.</li><li>On entering lady, the goddess of the lower regions does thus with her visitors.</li><li>The sixth gate he passed her through and drew her in, and he took away the bracelets of her hands and her feet.</li><li>Why keeper hast thou taken away the bracelets of my hands and my feet.</li><li>On entering lady, the goddess of the lower regions does thus with her visitors.</li><li>The seventh gate he passed her through and drew her in, and he took away the covering cloak of her body.</li><li>Why keeper hast thou taken away the covering cloak of my body.</li><li>On entering lady, the goddess of the lower regions does thus with her visitors.</li><li>When a long time Ishtar to Hades had descended;</li><li>Ninkigal saw her and at her presence was angry,</li><li>Ishtar did not consider and at her she swore.</li><li>Ninkigal her mouth opened and spake,</li><li>to Simtar her attendant a command she called:</li><li>Go Simtar [take Ishtar from] me and</li><li>take her out to . . . . Ishtar</li><li>diseased eyes strike her with,</li><li>diseased side strike her with,</li><li>diseased feet strike her with,</li><li>diseased heart strike her with,</li><li>diseased head strike her with,</li><li>to her the whole of her [strike with disease].</li><li>After Ishtar the lady [to Hades had descended],</li><li>with the cow the bull would not unite, and the ass the female ass would not approach;</li><li>and the female slave would not approach the vicinity of the master.</li><li>The master ceased in his command,</li><li>the female slave ceased in her gift.</li></ol>
<!-- /wp:list -->]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>470</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date><![CDATA[2019-08-13 18:10:33]]></wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt><![CDATA[2019-08-13 22:10:33]]></wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status><![CDATA[closed]]></wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status><![CDATA[closed]]></wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name><![CDATA[the-descent-of-ishtar-into-hades]]></wp:post_name>
		<wp:status><![CDATA[publish]]></wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type><![CDATA[story]]></wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password><![CDATA[]]></wp:post_password>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
										<category domain="region" nicename="asia"><![CDATA[Asia]]></category>
		<category domain="theme" nicename="confrontation-with-death"><![CDATA[confrontation with death]]></category>
		<category domain="demon" nicename="ereshkigal"><![CDATA[Ereshkigal]]></category>
		<category domain="author" nicename="george-smith"><![CDATA[George Smith]]></category>
		<category domain="theme" nicename="the-nature-of-evil"><![CDATA[the nature of evil]]></category>
		<category domain="region" nicename="145"><![CDATA[Western Asia]]></category>
						<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_edit_last]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[67389914]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							</item>
					<item>
		<title>The Devil and Tom Walker</title>
		<link>https://shortandsweet.wtf/story/the-devil-and-tom-walker/</link>
		<pubDate>Fri, 16 Aug 2019 22:35:17 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[eegering]]></dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://shortandsweet.wtf/?post_type=story&#038;p=508</guid>
		<description></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[A few miles from Boston in Massachusetts, there is a deep inlet, winding several miles into the interior of the country from Charles Bay, and terminating in a thickly-wooded swamp or morass. On one side of this inlet is a beautiful dark grove; on the opposite side the land rises abruptly from the water's edge into a high ridge, on which grow a few scattered oaks of great age and immense size.

Under one of these gigantic trees, according to old stories, there was a great amount of treasure buried by Kidd the pirate. The inlet allowed a facility to bring the money in a boat secretly and at night to the very foot of the hill; the elevation of the place permitted a good lookout to be kept that no one was at hand; while the remarkable trees formed good landmarks by which the place might easily be found again.
<!--more-->

The old stories add, moreover, that the devil presided at the hiding of the money, and took it under his guardianship; but this, it is well known, he always does with buried treasure, particularly when it has been ill-gotten. Be that as it may, Kidd never returned to recover his wealth; being shortly after seized at Boston, sent out to England, and there hanged for a pirate.

About the year 1727, just at the time that earthquakes were prevalent in New England, and shook many tall sinners down upon their knees, there lived near this place a meagre, miserly fellow, of the name of Tom Walker. He had a wife as miserly as himself: they were so miserly that they even conspired to cheat each other. Whatever the woman could lay hands on, she hid away; a hen could not cackle but she was on the alert to secure the new-laid egg.

Her husband was continually prying about to detect her secret hoards, and many and fierce were the conflicts that took place about what ought to have been common property. They lived in a forlorn-looking house that stood alone, and had an air of starvation. A few straggling savin-trees, emblems of sterility, grew near it; no smoke ever curled from its chimney; no traveller stopped at its door. A miserable horse, whose ribs were as articulate as the bars of a gridiron, stalked about a field, where a thin carpet of moss, scarcely covering the ragged beds of pudding-stone, tantalized and balked his hunger; and sometimes he would lean his head over the fence, look piteously at the passer-by, and seem to petition deliverance from this land of famine.

The house and its inmates had altogether a bad name. Tom's wife was a tall termagant, fierce of temper, loud of tongue, and strong of arm. Her voice was often heard in wordy warfare with her husband; and his face sometimes showed signs that their conflicts were not confined to words. No one ventured, however, to interfere between them. The lonely wayfarer shrunk within himself at the horrid clamour and clapper-clawing; eyed the den of discord askance; and hurried on his way, rejoicing, if a bachelor, in his celibacy.

One day that Tom Walker had been to a distant part of the neighbourhood, he took what he considered a short cut homeward, through the swamp. Like most short cuts, it was an ill-chosen route. The swamp was thickly grown with great gloomy pines and hemlocks, some of them ninety feet high, which made it dark at noonday, and a retreat for all the owls of the neighbourhood. It was full of pits and quagmires, partly covered with weeds and mosses, where the green surface often betrayed the traveller into a gulf of black, smothering mud: there were also dark and stagnant pools, the abodes of the tadpole, the bull-frog, and the water-snake; where the trunks of pines and hemlocks lay half-drowned, half-rotting, looking like alligators sleeping in the mire.

Tom had long been picking his way cautiously through this treacherous forest; stepping from tuft to tuft of rushes and roots, which afforded precarious footholds among deep sloughs; or pacing carefully, like a cat, along the prostrate trunks of trees; startled now and then by the sudden screaming of the bittern, or the quacking of a wild duck rising on the wing from some solitary pool.

At length he arrived at a firm piece of ground, which ran out like a peninsula into the deep bosom of the swamp. It had been one of the strongholds of the Indians during their wars with the first colonists. Here they had thrown up a kind of fort, which they had looked upon as almost impregnable, and had used as a place of refuge for their squaws and children. Nothing remained of the old Indian fort but a few embankments, gradually sinking to the level of the surrounding earth, and already overgrown in part by oaks and other forest trees, the foliage of which formed a contrast to the dark pines and hemlocks of the swamp.

It was late in the dusk of evening when Tom Walker reached the old fort, and he paused there awhile to rest himself. Any one but he would have felt unwilling to linger in this lonely, melancholy place, for the common people had a bad opinion of from the stories handed down from the time of the Indian wars when was asserted that the savages held incantations here, and made sacrifices to the evil spirit.

Tom Walker, however, was not man to be troubled with any fears of the kind. He reposed himself for some time on the trunk of fallen hemlock, listening to the boding cry of the tree-toad, and delving with his walking-staff into mound of black mould at his feet. As he turned up the soil unconsciously, his staff struck against something hard. He raked out of the vegetable mould, and lo! cloven skull, with an Indian tomahawk buried deep in lay before him. The rust on the weapon showed the time that had elapsed since this death-blow had been given. It was a dreary memento of the fierce struggle that had taken place in this last foothold of the Indian warriors.

"Humph!" said Tom Walker, as he gave it a kick to shake the dirt from it.

"Let that skull alone!" said gruff voice. Tom lifted up his eyes, and beheld great black man seated directly opposite him, on the stump of a tree.

He was exceedingly surprised, having neither heard nor seen any one approach; and he was still more perplexed on observing, as well as the gathering gloom would permit, that the stranger was neither negro nor Indian. It is true he was dressed in a rude half Indian garb, and had a red belt or sash swathed round his body; but his face was neither black nor copper-colour, but swarthy and dingy, and begrimed with soot, as if he had been accustomed to toil among fires and forges. He had a shock of coarse black hair, that stood out from his head in all directions, and bore an ax on his shoulder.

He scowled for a moment at Tom with a pair of great red eyes.

"What are you doing on my grounds?" said the black man, with a hoarse growling voice.

"Your grounds!" said Tom, with a sneer, "no more your grounds than mine; they belong to Deacon Peabody."

"Deacon Peabody be d—d," said the stranger, "as I flatter myself he will be, if he does not look more to his own sins and less to those of his neighbours. Look yonder, and see how Deacon Peabody is faring."

Tom looked in the direction that the stranger pointed, and beheld one of the great trees, fair and flourishing without, but rotten at the core, and saw that it had been nearly hewn through, so that the first high wind was likely to blow it down. On the bark of the tree was scored the name of Deacon Peabody, an eminent man, who had waxed wealthy by driving shrewd bargains with the Indians. He now looked around, and found most of the tall trees marked with the name of some great man of the colony, and all more or less scored by the ax. The one on which he had been seated, and which had evidently just been hewn down, bore the name of Crowninshield; and he recollected a mighty rich man of that name, who made a vulgar display of wealth, which it was whispered he had acquired by buccaneering.

"He's just ready for burning!" said the black man, with a growl of triumph. "You see I am likely to have a good stock of firewood for winter."

"But what right have you," said Tom, "to cut down Deacon Peabody's timber?"

"The right of a prior claim," said the other, "This woodland belonged to me long before one of your whitefaced race put foot upon the soil."

"And pray, who are you, if I may be so bold?" said Tom.

"Oh, I go by various names. I am the wild huntsman in some countries; the black miner in others. In this neighbourhood I am known by the name of the black woodsman. I am he to whom the red men consecrated this spot, and in honour of whom they now and then roasted a white man, by way of sweet-smelling sacrifice. Since the red men have been exterminated by you white savages, I amuse myself by presiding at the persecutions of Quakers and Anabaptists; I am the great patron and prompter of slave-dealers, and the grand-master of the Salem witches."

"The upshot of all which is, that, if I mistake not," said Tom, sturdily, "you are he commonly called Old Scratch."

"The same, at your service!" replied the black man, with a half civil nod.

Such was the opening of this interview, according to the old story; though it has almost too familiar an air to be credited. One would think that to meet with such a singular personage, in this wild, lonely place, would have shaken any man's nerves; but Tom was a hard-minded fellow, not easily daunted, and he had lived so long with a termagant wife, that he did not even fear the devil.

It is said that after this commencement they had a long and earnest conversation together, as Tom returned homeward. The black man told him of great sums of money buried by Kidd the pirate, under the oak-trees on the high ridge, not far from the morass. All these were under his command, and protected by his power, so that none could find them but such as propitiated his favour. These he offered to place within Tom Walker's reach, having conceived an especial kindness for him; but they were to be had only on certain conditions. What these conditions were may be easily surmised, though Tom never disclosed them publicly.

They must have been very hard, for he required time to think of them, and he was not a man to stick at trifles when money was in view. When they had reached the edge of the swamp, the stranger paused. "What proof have I that all you have been telling me is true?" said Tom. "There's my signature," said the black man, pressing his finger on Tom's forehead. So saying, he turned off among the thickets of the swamp, and seemed, as Tom said, to go down, down, down, into the earth, until nothing but his head and shoulders could be seen, and so on, until he totally disappeared.

When Tom reached home, he found the black print of a finger burnt, as it were, into his forehead, which nothing could obliterate.

The first news his wife had to tell him was the sudden death of Absalom Crowninshield, the rich buccaneer. It was announced in the papers with the usual flourish, that "A great man had fallen in Israel."

Tom recollected the tree which his black friend had just hewn down, and which was ready for burning.

"Let the freebooter roast," said Tom, "who cares!" He now felt convinced that all he had heard and seen was no illusion.

He was not prone to let his wife into his confidence; but as this was an uneasy secret, he willingly shared it with her. All her avarice was awakened at the mention of hidden gold, and she urged her husband to comply with the black man's terms, and secure what would make them wealthy for life.

However Tom might have felt disposed to sell himself to the Devil, he was determined not to do so to oblige his wife; so he flatly refused, out of the mere spirit of contradiction. Many and bitter were the quarrels they had on the subject; but the more she talked, the more resolute was Tom not to be damned to please her.

At length she determined to drive the bargain on her own account, and if she succeeded, to keep all the gain to herself. Being of the same fearless temper as her husband, she set off for the old Indian fort towards the close of a summer's day. She was many hours absent. When she came back, she was reserved and sullen in her replies. She spoke something of a black man, whom she had met about twilight hewing at the root of a tall tree. He was sulky, however, and would not come to terms: she was to go again with a propitiatory offering, but what it was she forbore to say.

The next evening she set off again for the swamp, with her apron heavily laden. Tom waited and waited for her, but in vain; midnight came, but she did not make her appearance: morning, noon, night returned, but still she did not come. Tom now grew uneasy for her safety, especially as he found she had carried off in her apron the silver tea-pot and spoons, and every portable article of value. Another night elapsed, another morning came; but no wife. In a word, she was never heard of more.

What was her real fate nobody knows, in consequence of so many pretending to know. It is one of those facts which have become confounded by a variety of historians. Some asserted that she lost her way among the tangled mazes of the swamp, and sank into some pit or slough; others, more charitable, hinted that she had eloped with the household booty, and made off to some other province; while others surmised that the tempter had decoyed her into a dismal quagmire, on the top of which her hat was found lying. In confirmation of this, it was said a great black man, with an ax on his shoulder, was seen late that very evening coming out of the swamp, carrying a bundle tied in a check apron, with an air of surly triumph.

The most current and probable story, however, observes, that Tom Walker grew so anxious about the fate of his wife and his property, that he set out at length to seek them both at the Indian fort. During a long summer's afternoon he searched about the gloomy place, but no wife was to be seen. He called her name repeatedly, but she was nowhere to be heard. The bittern alone responded to his voice, as he flew screaming by; or the bull-frog croaked dolefully from a neighbouring pool.

At length, it is said, just in the brown hour of twilight, when the owls began to hoot, and the bats to flit about, his attention was attracted by the clamour of carrion crows hovering about a cypress-tree. He looked up, and beheld a bundle tied in a check apron, and hanging in the branches of the tree, with a great vulture perched hard by, as if keeping watch upon it. He leaped with joy; for he recognized his wife's apron, and supposed it to contain the household valuables.

"Let us get hold of the property," said he, consolingly to himself, "and we will endeavour to do without the woman."

As he scrambled up the tree, the vulture spread its wide wings, and sailed off, screaming, into the deep shadows of the forest. Tom seized the checked apron, but, woeful sight! found nothing but a heart and liver tied up in it!

Such, according to this most authentic old story, was all that was to be found of Tom's wife. She had probably attempted to deal with the black man as she had been accustomed to deal with her husband; but though a female scold is generally considered a match for the devil, yet in this instance she appears to have had the worst of it.

She must have died game, however; for it is said Tom noticed many prints of cloven feet deeply stamped about the tree, and found handfuls of hair, that looked as if they had been plucked from the coarse black shock of the woodman. Tom knew his wife's prowess by experience. He shrugged his shoulders, as he looked at the signs of a fierce clapper-clawing. "Egad," said he to himself, "Old Scratch must have had a tough time of it!"

Tom consoled himself for the loss of his property, with the loss of his wife, for he was a man of fortitude. He even felt something like gratitude towards the black woodman, who, he considered, had done him a kindness. He sought, therefore, to cultivate a further acquaintance with him, but for some time without success; the old black-legs played shy, for whatever people may think, he is not always to be had for calling for: he knows how to play his cards when pretty sure of his game.

At length, it is said, when delay had whetted Tom's eagerness to the quick, and prepared him to agree to anything rather than not gain the promised treasure, he met the black man one evening in his usual woodman's dress, with his ax on his shoulder, sauntering along the swamp, and humming a tune. He affected to receive Tom's advances with great indifference, made brief replies, and went on humming his tune.

By degrees, however, Tom brought him to business, and they began to haggle about the terms on which the former was to have the pirate's treasure. There was one condition which need not be mentioned, being generally understood in all cases where the devil grants favours; but there were others about which, though of less importance, he was inflexibly obstinate.

He insisted that the money found through his means should be employed in his service. He proposed, therefore, that Tom should employ it in the black traffic; that is to say, that he should fit out a slave-ship. This, however, Tom resolutely refused: he was bad enough in all conscience; but the devil himself could not tempt him to turn slave-trader.

Finding Tom so squeamish on this point, he did not insist upon but proposed, instead, that he should turn usurer; the devil being extremely anxious for the increase of usurers, looking upon them as his peculiar people.

To this no objections were made, for it was just to Tom's taste.

"You shall open a broker's shop in Boston next month," said the black man.

"I'll do tomorrow, you wish," said Tom Walker.

"You shall lend money at two per cent. a month."

"Egad, I'll charge four!" replied Tom Walker.

"You shall extort bonds, foreclose mortgages, drive the merchants to bankruptcy" —

"I'll drive them to the d—l," cried Tom Walker.

"You are the usurer for my money!" said black-legs with delight. "When will you want the rhino?"

"This very night."

"Done!" said the devil.

"Done!" said Tom Walker.—So they shook hands and struck a bargain.

A few days' time saw Tom Walker seated behind his desk in a counting-house in Boston.
His reputation for a ready-moneyed man, who would lend money out for a good consideration, soon spread abroad. Everybody remembers the time of Governor Belcher, when money was particularly scarce. It was a time of paper credit. The country had been deluged with government bills, the famous Land Bank had been established; there had been a rage for speculating; the people had run mad with schemes for new settlements; for building cities in the wilderness; land-jobbers went about with maps of grants, and townships, and Eldorados, lying nobody knew where, but which everybody was ready to purchase.

In a word, the great speculating fever which breaks out every now and then in the country, had raged to an alarming degree, and everybody was dreaming of making sudden fortunes from nothing. As usual the fever had subsided; the dream had gone off, and the imaginary fortunes with it; the patients were left in doleful plight, and the whole country resounded with the consequent cry of "hard times."

At this propitious time of public distress did Tom Walker set up as usurer in Boston. His door was soon thronged by customers. The needy and adventurous; the gambling speculator; the dreaming land-jobber; the thriftless tradesman; the merchant with cracked credit; in short, every one driven to raise money by desperate means and desperate sacrifices, hurried to Tom Walker.
Thus Tom was the universal friend of the needy, and acted like a "friend in need"; that is to say, he always exacted good pay and good security. In proportion to the distress of the applicant was the hardness of his terms. He accumulated bonds and mortgages; gradually squeezed his customers closer and closer: and sent them at length, dry as a sponge, from his door.

In this way he made money hand over hand; became a rich and mighty man, and exalted his cocked hat upon 'Change. He built himself, as usual, a vast house, out of ostentation; but left the greater part of it unfinished and unfurnished, out of parsimony. He even set up a carriage in the fulness of his vainglory, though he nearly starved the horses which drew it; and as the ungreased wheels groaned and screeched on the axle-trees, you would have thought you heard the souls of the poor debtors he was squeezing.

As Tom waxed old, however, he grew thoughtful. Having secured the good things of this world, he began to feel anxious about those of the next. He thought with regret on the bargain he had made with his black friend, and set his wits to work to cheat him out of the conditions. He became, therefore, all of a sudden, a violent church-goer. He prayed loudly and strenuously, as if heaven were to be taken by force of lungs. Indeed, one might always tell when he had sinned most during the week, by the clamour of his Sunday devotion. The quiet Christians who had been modestly and steadfastly travelling Zionward, were struck with self-reproach at seeing themselves so suddenly outstripped in their career by this new-made convert.

Tom was as rigid in religious as in money matters; he was a stern supervisor and censurer of his neighbours, and seemed to think every sin entered up to their account became a credit on his own side of the page. He even talked of the expediency of reviving the persecution of Quakers and Anabaptists. In a word, Tom's zeal became as notorious as his riches.

Still, in spite of all this strenuous attention to forms, Tom had a lurking dread that the devil, after all, would have his due. That he might not be taken unawares, therefore, it is said he always carried a small Bible in his coat-pocket. He had also a great folio Bible on his counting-house desk, and would frequently be found reading it when people called on business; on such occasions he would lay his green spectacles in the book, to mark the place, while he turned round to drive some usurious bargain.

Some say that Tom grew a little crack-brained in his old days, and that, fancying his end approaching, he had his horse new shod, saddled and bridled, and buried with his feet uppermost; because he supposed that at the last day the world would be turned upside down; in which case he should find his horse standing ready for mounting, and he was determined at the worst to give his old friend a run for it. This, however, is probably a mere old wives' fable. If he really did take such a precaution, it was totally superfluous; at least so says the authentic old legend; which closes his story in the following manner.

One hot summer afternoon in the dog-days, just as a terrible black thunder-gust was coming up, Tom sat in his counting-house, in his white linen cap and India silk morning-gown. He was on the point of foreclosing a mortgage, by which he would complete the ruin of an unlucky land-speculator for whom he had professed the greatest friendship. The poor land-jobber begged him to grant a few months' indulgence. Tom had grown testy and irritated, and refused another day.

"My family will be ruined, and brought upon the parish," said the land-jobber.

"Charity begins at home," replied Tom; "I must take care of myself in these hard times."

"You have made so much money out of me," said the speculator.

Tom lost his patience and his piety. "The devil take me," said he, "if I have made a farthing!"

Just then there were three loud knocks at the street-door. He stepped out to see who was there.

A black man was holding a black horse, which neighed and stamped with impatience.

"Tom, you're come for," said the black fellow, gruffly.

Tom shrank back, but too late. He had left his little Bible at the bottom of his coat-pocket, and his big Bible on the desk buried under the mortgage he was about to foreclose: never was sinner taken more unawares. The black man whisked him like a child into the saddle, gave the horse the lash, and away he galloped, with Tom on his back, in the midst of the thunderstorm. The clerks stuck their pens behind their ears, and stared after him from the windows. Away went Tom Walker, dashing down the street; his white cap bobbing up and down; his morning-gown fluttering in the wind, and his steed striking fire out of the pavement at every bound. When the clerks turned to look for the black man, he had disappeared.

Tom Walker never returned to foreclose the mortgage. A countryman, who lived on the border of the swamp, reported that in the height of the thunder-gust he had heard a great clattering of hoofs and a howling along the road, and running to the window caught sight of a figure, such as I have described, on a horse that galloped like mad across the fields, over the hills, and down into the black hemlock swamp towards the old Indian fort; and that shortly after a thunder-bolt falling in that direction seemed to set the whole forest in a blaze.

The good people of Boston shook their heads and shrugged their shoulders, but had been so much accustomed to witches and goblins, and tricks of the devil, in all kinds of shapes, from the first settlement of the colony, that they were not so much horror-struck as might have been expected. Trustees were appointed to take charge of Tom's effects. There was nothing, however, to administer upon. On searching his coffers, all his bonds and mortgages were found reduced to cinders. In place of gold and silver, his iron chest was filled with chips and shavings; two skeletons lay in his stable instead of his half-starved horses, and the very next day his great house took fire and was burnt to the ground.

Such was the end of Tom Walker and his ill-gotten wealth. Let all griping money-brokers lay this story to heart. The truth of it is not to be doubted. The very hole under the oak-trees, whence he dug Kidd's money, is to be seen to this day; and the neighbouring swamp and old Indian fort are often haunted in stormy nights by a figure on horseback, in morning-gown and white cap, which is doubtless the troubled spirit of the usurer. In fact, the story has resolved itself into a proverb, and is the origin of that popular saying, so prevalent throughout New England, of "The Devil and Tom Walker."]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>508</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date><![CDATA[2019-08-16 18:35:17]]></wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt><![CDATA[2019-08-16 22:35:17]]></wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status><![CDATA[closed]]></wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status><![CDATA[closed]]></wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name><![CDATA[the-devil-and-tom-walker]]></wp:post_name>
		<wp:status><![CDATA[publish]]></wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type><![CDATA[story]]></wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password><![CDATA[]]></wp:post_password>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
										<category domain="demon" nicename="devil"><![CDATA[Devil]]></category>
		<category domain="region" nicename="150"><![CDATA[Europe]]></category>
		<category domain="theme" nicename="initiation"><![CDATA[initiation]]></category>
		<category domain="theme" nicename="retreat-from-involvement"><![CDATA[retreat from involvement]]></category>
		<category domain="theme" nicename="the-mysterious-stranger"><![CDATA[the mysterious stranger]]></category>
		<category domain="theme" nicename="the-nature-of-evil"><![CDATA[the nature of evil]]></category>
		<category domain="author" nicename="washington-irving"><![CDATA[Washington Irving]]></category>
						<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_edit_last]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[67389914]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							</item>
					<item>
		<title>Marya-Morevna</title>
		<link>https://shortandsweet.wtf/story/marya-morevna/</link>
		<pubDate>Tue, 20 Aug 2019 20:03:13 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[eegering]]></dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://shortandsweet.wtf/?post_type=story&#038;p=529</guid>
		<description></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[In a certain kingdom there lived a Prince Ivan. He had three sisters. The first was the Princess Marya, the second the Princess Olga, the third the Princess Anna. When their father and mother lay at the point of death, they had thus enjoined their son:— "Give your sisters in marriage to the very first suitors who come to woo them. Don't go keeping them by you!"

They died and the Prince buried them, and then, to solace his grief, he went with his sisters into the garden green to stroll. Suddenly the sky was covered by a black cloud; a terrible storm arose.

<!--more-->

"Let us go home, sisters!" he cried.

Hardly had they got into the palace, when the thunder pealed, the ceiling split open, and into the room where they were, came flying a falcon bright. The Falcon smote upon the ground, became a brave youth, and said:

"Hail, Prince Ivan! Before I came as a guest, but now I have come as a wooer! I wish to propose for your sister, the Princess Marya."

"If you find favor in the eyes of my sister, I will not interfere with her wishes. Let her marry you in God's name!"

The Princess Marya gave her consent; the Falcon married her and bore her away into his own realm.

Days follow days, hours chase hours; a whole year goes by. One day Prince Ivan and his two sisters went out to stroll in the garden green. Again there arose a stormcloud with whirlwind and lightning.

"Let us go home, sisters!" cried the Prince. Scarcely had they entered the palace, when the thunder crashed, the roof burst into a blaze, the ceiling split in twain, and in flew an eagle. The Eagle smote upon the ground and became a brave youth.

"Hail, Prince Ivan! Before I came as a guest, but now I have come as a wooer!"

And he asked for the hand of the Princess Olga. Prince Ivan replied:

"If you find favor in the eyes of the Princess Olga, then let her marry you. I will not interfere with her liberty of choice."

The Princess Olga gave her consent and married the Eagle. The Eagle took her and carried her off to his own kingdom.

Another year went by. Prince Ivan said to his youngest sister:

"Let us go out and stroll in the garden green!"

They strolled about for a time. Again there arose a stormcloud, with whirlwind and lightning.

"Let us return home, sister!" said he.

They returned home, but they hadn't had time to sit down when the thunder crashed, the ceiling split open, and in flew a raven. The Raven smote upon the floor and became a brave youth. The former youths had been handsome, but this one was handsomer still.

"Well, Prince Ivan! Before I came as a guest, but now I have come as a wooer. Give me the Princess Anna to wife."

"I won't interfere with my sisters freedom. If you gain her affections, let her marry you."

So the Princess Anna married the Raven, and he bore her away to his own realm. Prince Ivan was left alone. A whole year he lived without his sisters; then he grew weary, and said:—

"I will set out in search of my sisters."

He got ready for the journey, he rode and rode, and one day he saw a whole army lying dead on the plain. He cried aloud,

"If there be a living man there, let him make answer! who has slain this mighty host?"

There replied unto him a living man:

"All this mighty host has been slain by the fair Princess Marya Morevna."

Prince Ivan rode further on, and came to a white tent, and forth came to meet him the fair Princess Marya Morevna.

"Hail Prince!" says she, "whither does God send you? and is it of your free will or against your will?"

Prince Ivan replied, "Not against their will do brave youths ride!"

"Well, if your business be not pressing, tarry awhile in my tent."

Thereat was Prince Ivan glad. He spent two nights in the tent, and he found favor in the eyes of Marya Morevna, and she married him. The fair Princess, Marya Morevna, carried him off into her own realm.

They spent some time together, and then the Princess took it into her head to go a warring. So she handed over all the housekeeping affairs to Prince Ivan, and gave him these instructions:

"Go about everywhere, keep watch over everything, only do not venture to look into that closet there."

He couldn't help doing so. The moment Marya Morevna had gone he rushed to the closet, pulled open the door, and looked in — there hung Koshchei the Deathless, fettered by twelve chains. Then Koshchei entreated Prince Ivan, saying—

"Have pity upon me and give me to drink! Ten years long have I been here in torment, neither eating or drinking; my throat is utterly dried up."

The Prince gave him a bucketful of water; he drank it up and asked for more, saying:

"A single bucket of water will not quench my thirst; give me more!"

The Prince gave him a second bucketful. Koshchei drank it up and asked for a third, and when he had swallowed the third bucketful, he regained his former strength, gave his chains a shake, and broke all twelve at once.

" Thanks, Prince Ivan!" cried Koshchei the deathless, "now you will sooner see your own ears than Marya Morevna" and out of the window he flew in the shape of a terrible whirlwind. And he came up with the fair Princess Marya Morevna as she was going her way, laid hold of her, and carried her off home with him. But Prince Ivan wept full sore, and he arrayed himself and set out a wandering, saying to himself: "Whatever happens, I will go and look for Marya Morevna!"

One day passed, another day passed: at the dawn of the third day he saw a wondrous palace, and by the side of the palace stood an oak, and on the oak sat a falcon bright. Down flew the Falcon from the oak, smote upon the ground, turned into a brave youth and cried aloud:

"Ha, dear brother-in-law! how deals the Lord with you?"

Out came running the Princess Marya, joyfully greeted her brother Ivan, and began enquiring after his health, and telling him all about herself. The Prince spent three days with them; then he said:

"I cannot abide with you; I must go in search of my wife, the fair Princess Marya Morevna."

"Hard will it be for you to find her," answered the Falcon. "At all events leave with us your silver spoon. We will look at it and remember you." So Prince Ivan left his silver spoon at the Falcon's, and went on his way again.

On he went one day, on he went another day, and by the dawn of the third day he saw a palace still grander than the former one, and hard by the palace stood an oak, and on the oak sat an eagle. Down flew the eagle from the oak, smote upon the ground, turned into a brave youth, and cried aloud:

"Rise up, Princess Olga! Hither comes our brother dear!"

The Princess Olga immediately ran to meet him, and began kissing him and embracing him, asking after his health and telling him all about herself. With them Prince Ivan stopped three days; then he said:

"I cannot stay here any longer. I am going to look for my wife, the fair Princess Marya Morevna."

"Нагd will it be for you to find her," replied the Eagle, "Leave with us a silver fork. We will look at it and remember you."

He left a silver fork behind, and went his way. He travelled one day, he travelled two days; at daybreak on the third day he saw a palace grander than the first two, and near the palace stood an oak, and on the oak sat a raven. Down flew the Raven from the oak, smote upon the ground, turned into a brave youth, and cried aloud:

"Princess Anna, come forth quickly! our brother is coming!"

Out ran the Princess Anna, greeted him joyfully, and began kissing and embracing him, asking after his health and telling him all about herself. Prince Ivan stayed with them three days; then he said:

"Farewell ! I am going to look for my wife, the fair Princess Marya Morevna."

"Hard will it be for you to find her," replied the Raven, "Anyhow, leave your silver snuff-box with us. We will look at it and remember you."

The Prince handed over his silver snuff-box, took his leave and went his way. One day he went, another day he went, and on the third day he came to where Marya Morevna was. She caught sight of her love, flung her arms around his neck, burst into tears, and exclaimed:

"Oh, Prince Ivan! why did you disobey me, and go looking into the closet and letting out Koshchei the Deathless?"

"Forgive me, Marya Morevna! Remember not the past; much better fly with me while Koshchei the Deathless is out of sight. Perhaps he won't catch us."

So they got ready and fled. Now Koshchei was out hunting. Towards evening he was returning home, when his good steed stumbled beneath him.

" Why stumblest thou, sorry jade? scentest thou some ill?"

The steed replied:

"Prince Ivan has come and carried off Marya Morevna."

"Is it possible to catch them?"

"Is it possible to sow wheat, to wait till it grows up, to reap it and thresh it, to grind to flour, to make five pies of it, to eat those pies, and then to start in pursuit—and even then to be in time."

Koshchei galloped off and caught up Prince Ivan.

"Now," says he, " this time will forgive you, in return for your kindness in giving me water to drink. And a second time I will forgive you; but the third time beware! I will cut you to
bits."

Then he took Marya Morevna from him, and carried her off. But Prince Ivan sat down on a stone and burst into tears. He wept and wept — and then returned back again to Marya Morevna. Now Koshchei the Deathless happened not to be at home.

"Let us fly, Marya Morevna!"

"Ah, Prince Ivan he will catch us."

"Suppose he does catch us. At all events we shall have spent an hour or two together."

So they got ready and fled. As Koshchei the Deathless was returning home, his good steed stumbled beneath him.

"Why stumblest thou, sorry jade? Scentest thou some ill?"

"Prince Ivan has come and carried off Marya Morevna."

"Is possible to catch them?"

"It is possible to sow barley, to wait till grows up, to reap it and thresh it, to brew beer, to drink ourselves drunk on it, to sleep our fill, and then to set off in pursuit—and yet to be in time."

Koshchei galloped off, caught up Prince Ivan:

"Didn't I tell you that you should not see Marya Morevna any more than your own ears?"

And he took her away and carried her off home with him.

Prince Ivan was left there alone. He wept and wept; then he went back again after Marya Morevna. Koshchei happened to be away from home at that moment.

"Let us fly, Marya Morevna."

"Ah, Prince Ivan! He sure to catch us and hew you pieces."

"Let him hew away! I cannot live without you."

So they got ready and fled.

Koshchei the Deathless was returning home when his good steed stumbled beneath him.

" Why stumblest thou? scentest thou any ill?"

"Prince Ivan has come and has carried off Marya Morevna."

Koshchei galloped off, caught Prince Ivan, chopped him into little pieces, put them in a barrel, smeared it with pitch and bound it with iron hoops, and flung it into the blue sea. But Marya Morevna he carried off home.

At that very time, the silver turned black which Prince Ivan had left with his brothers-in-law.

"Ah!" said they, "the evil is accomplished sure enough!"

Then the Eagle hurried to the blue sea, caught hold of the barrel, and dragged it ashore; the Falcon flew away for the Water of Life, and the Raven for the Water of Death.

Afterwards they all three met, broke open the barrel, took out the remains of Prince Ivan, washed them, and put them together in fitting order. The Raven sprinkled them with the Water of Death — the pieces joined together, the body became whole. The Falcon sprinkled it with the Water of Life — Prince Ivan shuddered, stood up, and said:

"Ah! what a time I've been sleeping!"

"You'd have gone on sleeping a good deal longer, if it hadn't been for us," replied his brothers-in-law. "Now come and pay us a visit."

"Not so, brothers; I shall go and look for Marya Morevna." And when he had found her, he said to her:
"Find out from Koshchei the Deathless whence he got so good a steed."

So Marya Morevna chose a favorable moment, and began asking Koshchei about it. Koshchei replied:

"Beyond thrice nine lands, in the thirtieth kingdom, on the other side of the fiery river, there lives a Baba Yaga. She has so good a mare that she flies right round the world on it every day. And she has many other splendid mares. I watched her herds for three days without losing a single mare, and in return for that the Baba Yaga gave me a foal."

"But how did you get across the fiery river?"

" Why, I've a handkerchief of this kind—when I wave it thrice on the right hand, there springs up a very lofty bridge and the fire cannot reach it."

Marya Morevna listened to all this, and repeated it to Prince Ivan, and she carried off the handkerchief and gave it to him. So he managed to get across the fiery river, and then went on to the Baba Yaga's. Long went he on without getting anything either to eat or to drink. At last he came across an outlandish bird and its young ones. Says Prince Ivan:

"I'll eat one of these chickens."

"Don't eat it, Prince Ivan!" begs the outlandish bird; "some time or other I'll do you a good turn."

He went on farther and saw a hive of bees in the forest.

"I'll get a bit of honeycomb," says he.

"Don't disturb my honey, Prince Ivan!" exclaims the queen bee; "some time or other I'll do you a good turn."

So he didn't disturb but went on. Presently there met him a lioness with her cub.

"Anyhow I'll eat this lion cub," says he; " I'm so hungry, I feel quite unwell!"

"Please let us alone, Prince Ivan" begs the lioness; "some time or other I'll do you good turn."

"Very well; have it your own way," says he.

Hungry and faint he wandered on, walked farther and farther, and at last came to where stood the house of the Baba Yaga. Round the house were set twelve poles in circle, and on each of eleven of these poles was stuck human head, the twelfth alone remained unoccupied.

"Hail, granny!"

"Hail, Prince Ivan! wherefore have you come? Is it of your own accord, or on compulsion?"

" have come to earn from you heroic steed."

"So be it, Prince you won't have to serve year with me, but just three days. If you take good care of my mares, I'll give you a heroic steed. But if you don't — why then you mustn't be annoyed at finding your head stuck on top of the last pole up there."

Prince Ivan agreed to these terms. The Baba Yaga gave him food and drink, and bid him set about his business. But the moment he had driven the mares afield, they cocked up their tails, and away they tore across the meadows in all directions. Before the Prince had time to look round, they were all out of sight. Thereupon he began to weep and to disquiet himself, and then he sat down upon a stone and went to sleep. But when the sun was near its setting, the outlandish bird came flying up to him, and awakened him saying:—

"Arise, Prince Ivan! the mares are at home now."

The Prince arose and returned home. There the Baba Yaga was storming and raging at her mares, and shrieking :—

"Whatever did ye come home for?"

"Ноw could we help coming home?" said they. "There came flying birds from every part of the world, and all but pecked our eyes out."

"Well, well! to-morrow don't go galloping over the meadows, but disperse amid the thick forests."

Prince Ivan slept all night. In the morning the Baba Yaga says to him:—

"Mind, Prince! if you don't take good care of the mares, if you lose merely one of them—your bold head will be stuck on that pole!"

He drove the mares afield. Immediately they cocked up their tails and dispersed among the thick forests. Again did the Prince sit down on the stone, weep and weep, and then go to sleep. The sun went down behind the forest. Up came running the lioness.

"Arise, Prince Ivan! The mares are all collected."

Prince Ivan arose and went home. More than ever did the Baba Yaga storm at her mares and shriek:—

"Whatever did ye come back home for?"

"How could we help coming back? Beasts of prey came running at us from all parts of the world, all but tore us utterly to pieces."

"Well, to-morrow run off into the blue sea."

Again did Prince Ivan sleep through the night. Next morning the Baba Yaga sent him forth to watch the mares:

"If you don't take good care of them," says she, "your bold head will be stuck on that pole!"

He drove the mares afield. Immediately they cocked up their tails, disappeared from sight, and fled into the blue sea. There they stood, up to their necks in water. Prince Ivan sat down on the stone, wept, and fell asleep. But when the sun had set behind the forest, up came flying a bee and said:—

"Arise, Prince! The mares are all collected. But when you get home, don't let the Baba Yaga set eyes on you, but go into the stable and hide behind the mangers. There you will find a sorry colt rolling in the muck. Do you steal and at the dead of night ride away from the house."

Prince Ivan arose, slipped into the stable, and lay down behind the mangers, while the Baba Yaga was storming away at her mares and shrieking —

"Why did ye come back?"

"How could we help coming back? There came flying bees in countless numbers from all parts of the world, and began stinging us on all sides till the blood came!"

The Baba Yaga went to sleep. In the dead of the night Prince Ivan stole the sorry colt, saddled it, jumped on its back, and galloped away to the fiery river. When he came to that river he waved the handkerchief three times on the right hand, and suddenly, springing goodness knows whence, there hung across the river, high in the air, splendid bridge. The Prince rode across the bridge and waved the handkerchief twice only on the left hand there remained across the river a thin — ever so thin a bridge!

When the Baba Yaga got up in the morning, the sorry colt was not to be seen. Off she set in pursuit. At full speed did she fly in her iron mortar, urging on with the pestle, sweeping away her traces with the broom. She dashed up to the fiery river, gave glance, and said, " A capital bridge!" She drove on to the bridge, but had only got half-way when the bridge broke in two, and the Baba Yaga went flop into the river. There truly did she meet with a cruel death!

Prince Ivan fattened up the colt in the green meadows, and it turned into a wondrous steed. Then he rode to where Marya Morevna was. She came running out, and flung herself on his neck, crying:—

"By what means has God brought you back to life?"

"Thus and thus," says he. "Now come along with me."

"I am afraid, Prince Ivan! If Koshchei catches us, you will be cut in pieces again."

"No, he won't catch us! I have a splendid heroic steed now; it flies just like a bird." So they got on its back and rode away.

Koshchei the Deathless was returning home when his horse stumbled beneath him.

"What art thou stumbling for, sorry jade? dost thou scent any ill?"

"Prince Ivan has come and carried off Marya Morevna."

"Can we catch them?"

"God knows! Prince Ivan has a horse now which is better than I."

"Well, I can't stand it," says Koshchei the Deathless. "I will pursue."

After a time he came up with Prince Ivan, lighted on the ground, and was going to chop him up with his sharp sword. But at that moment Prince Ivan's horse smote Koshchei the Deathless full swing with its hoof, and cracked his skull, and the Prince made an end of him with a club. Afterwards the Prince heaped up a pile of wood, set fire to it, burnt Koshchei the Deathless on the pyre, and scattered his ashes to the wind. Then Marya Morevna mounted Koshchei's horse and Prince Ivan got on his own, and they rode away to visit first the Raven, and then the Eagle, and then the Falcon. Wherever they went they met with a joyful greeting.

"Ah, Prince Ivan! why we never expected to see you again. Well, it wasn't for nothing that you gave yourself so much trouble. Such a beauty as Marya Morevna one might search for all the world over — and never find one like her ! "

And so they visited, and they feasted; and afterwards they went off to their own realm.]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>529</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date><![CDATA[2019-08-20 16:03:13]]></wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt><![CDATA[2019-08-20 20:03:13]]></wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status><![CDATA[closed]]></wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status><![CDATA[closed]]></wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name><![CDATA[marya-morevna]]></wp:post_name>
		<wp:status><![CDATA[publish]]></wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type><![CDATA[story]]></wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password><![CDATA[]]></wp:post_password>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
										<category domain="demon" nicename="baba-yaga"><![CDATA[Baba Yaga]]></category>
		<category domain="region" nicename="151"><![CDATA[Eastern Europe]]></category>
		<category domain="theme" nicename="the-nature-of-evil"><![CDATA[the nature of evil]]></category>
		<category domain="author" nicename="william-r-s-ralston"><![CDATA[William R. S. Ralston]]></category>
		<category domain="theme" nicename="woman-in-a-male-society"><![CDATA[woman in a male society]]></category>
						<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_edit_last]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[67389914]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							</item>
					<item>
		<title>The Banshee&#039;s Comb (Chapter 1)</title>
		<link>https://shortandsweet.wtf/story/the-banshees-comb-chapter-1/</link>
		<pubDate>Tue, 20 Aug 2019 21:27:27 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[eegering]]></dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://shortandsweet.wtf/?post_type=story&#038;p=531</guid>
		<description></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[THE DIPLOMACY OF BRIDGET

I

'TWAS the mendin' of clothes that All Sowls' afthernoon in Elizabeth Ann Egan's kitchen that naturally brought up the subject of husbands an' the best ways to manage them. An' if there's one thing more than another that makes me take me hat off to the women, 'tis the owdacious way the most down-throdden of their sex will brag about her blaggard husband.

<!--more-->

Not that ayther one or the other of the foive busy-tongued and busy-fingered neighbour women who bint above their sewing or knitting that afthernoon were down-throdden; be no manner of manes; far, far from it. They were so filled with matrimonial contintedness that they fairly thrampled down one another to be first in praising the wondherful men of their choice. Every woman proudly claimed to own an' conthrol the handsomest, loikeliest man that ever throd in brogues.

They talked so fast an' they talked so loud that 'twas a thryin' long while before meek-woiced little Margit Doyle could squeege her husband, Dan'l John, sideways into the argyment. An' even when she did get him to the fore, the other women had appropryated all the hayroic qualifications for their own men, so that there was nothing left for Dan'l but the common lavings; an' that dayprivation nettled Margit an' vexed her sore. But she took her chanst when it came, poor as it was, an' boulted in.

Jabbing the air as though her needle were a dagger, she broke into the discoorse.

"I wouldn't thrade my Dan for the King of Rooshia or the Imperor of Chiney," says she, peering dayfiant around the room. No one sided with that raymark, an' no one argyed agin it, an' this vexed her the more.

"The Kingdom of Chiney is where the most supharior tay comes from," says Caycelia Crow. She was a large, solemn woman, was Misthress Crow, an a gr-r-reat histhorian.

"No," says Margit, scorning the intherruption, "not if the two men were rowled into one," says she.

"Why," says Caycelia Crow, an' her deep woice tolled like a passing bell "why," says she, "should any dacint woman be wantin' to marry one of thim haythen Imperors? Sure they're all ambiguious," she says, looking around proud of the grand worrud.

Elizabeth Ann sthopped the spinning-wheel the betther to listen, while the others turned bothered faces to the histhorian.

"Ambiguious," says Misthress Crow, raisin' her woice in the middle part of the worrud; "ambiguious," she says again, "manes that accordin' to the laygal laws of some furrin parts, a man may marry four or five wives if he has a mind to."

At this Margit bristled up like a bantam-hin.

"Do you mane to say, Caycelia Crow," says she, dhroppin' in her lap the weskit she was mendin', "do you intind to substantiate that I'm wishin' to marry the Imperor of Chiney, or," she says, her woice growin' high an' cutting as an east wind, "do you wish to inferentiate that if my Dan'l had the lave he'd be ambiguious? Will you plaze tell these friends an' neighbours," she says, wavin' a hand, "which of the two of us you was minded to insinuate against?"

The attackt was so sudden an' so unexpected that Misthress Crow was too bewildhered to dayfind herself. The poor woman only sat starin' stupid at Margit.

The others sunk back in their chairs spacheless with consternaytion till Mollie Scanlan, wishin' to pacificate the sitiwation, an' winkin' friendly at Caycelia, spoke up sootherin'.

"Thrue for ye, Margit Doyle," says she. "What kind of talk is that for ye to be talkin', Caycelia?" says she. "Sure if Dan'l John were to be med the Imperor of Chiney to-morrow he'd hesitate an' dayliberate a long time before bringin' in one of them ambiguious women to you an' the childher. I'd like to see him thry it. It'ud be a sore an' a sorrowful day for him, I'm thinkin'."

At thim worruds, Margit, in her mind's eye, saw Dan'l John standin' ferninst her with an ambiguious haythen woman on aich side of him, an' the picture riled the blood in her heart.

"Oh, ho!" says she, turning on poor, shrinkin' Mollie with a smile, an' that same smile had loaded guns an' pistols in it. "An' will you plaze be so kind an' condesinden', Misthress Scanlan," says she, "to explain what you ever saw or heerd tell of in my Dan'l John's actions, that'ud make you think he'd contimplate such schoundrel endayvours," says she, thrimblin'.

The only answer to the question was from the tay-kettle. It was singin' high an' impident on the hob.

Now, Bridget O'Gill, knowin' woman that she was, had wisely kept out of the discoorse. She sat apart, calmly knittin' one of Darby's winther stockings. As she listened, howsumever, she couldn't keep back a sly smile that lifted one corner of her mouth.

"Isn't it a poor an' a pittiful case," said Misthress Doyle, glaring savage from one to the other, "that a dacint man, the father of noine childher, eight of them livin', an' one gone for a sojer—isn't it a burnin' shame," she says, whumperin', "that such a daycint man must have his char-ack-ther thrajuiced before his own wife— Will you be so good as to tell me what you're laughing at, Bridget O'Gill, ma'am?" she blazed.

Bridget, flutthering guilty, thried to hide the misfortunate smile, but 'twas too late.

"Bekase, if it is my husband you're mocking at," says Margit, "let me tell you, fair an' plain, his ayquils don't live in the County of Tipperary, let alone this parish! 'Tis thrue," she says, tossin' her head, "he hasn't spint six months with the Good People—he knows nothin' of the fairies—but he has more sinse than those that have. At any rate, he isn't afeard of ghosts like a knowledgeable man that I could mintion."

That last thrust touched a sore spot in the heart of Bridget. Although Darby O'Gill would fight a dozen livin' men, if needful, 'twas well known he had an unraysonable fear of ghosts. So, Bridget said never a worrud, but her brown eyes began to sparkle, an' her red lips were dhrawn up to the size of a button.

Margit saw how hard she'd hit, an' she wint on thriumphant.

"My Dan'l John'ud sleep in a churchyard. He's done it," says she, crowin'.

Bridget could hould in no longer. "I'd be sore an' sorry," she says, "if a husband of mine were druv to do such a thing as that for the sake of a little pace and quiet," says she, turnin' her chowlder.

Tare an' 'ounds, but that was the sthroke! "The Lord bless us!" mutthered Mollie Scanlan. Margit's mind wint up in the air an' staid there whirlin', whilst she herself sat gasping an' panting for a rayply. 'Twas a thrilling, suspenseful minute.

The chiney shepherd and shepherdess on the mantel sthopped ogling their eyes an' looked shocked at aich other; at the same time Bob, the linnet, in his wooden cage at the door, quit his singin' an' cocked his head the betther to listen; the surprised tay-kettle gave a gasp an' a gurgle, an' splutthered over the fire. In the turrible silence Elizabeth Egan got up to wet the tay. Settin' the taypot in the fender she spoke, an' she spoke raysentful.

"Any sinsible man is afeard of ghosts," says she.

"Oh, indade," says Margit, ketching her breath. "Is that so? Well, sinsible or onsinsible," says she, "this will be Halloween, an' there's not a man in the parish who would walk past the churchyard up to Cormac McCarthy's house, where the Banshee keened last night, except my Dan'l!" says she, thriumphant.

The hurt pride in Bridget rose at that an' forced from her angry lips a foolish promise.

"Huh! we hear ducks talkin'," she says, coolly rowling up Darby's stocking, an' sticking the needle in the ball of yarn. "This afthernoon I was at Cormac McCarthy's," she says, "an' there wasn't a bit of tay in the house for poor Eileen, so I promised Cormac I'd send him up a handful. Now, be the same token, I promise you my Darby will make no bones of going on that errant this night."

"Ho! ho! ho!" laughed Margit. "If he has the courage to do it bid him sthop in to me on his way back, an' I'll send to you a fine settin' of eggs from my black Spanish hin."

What sharp worrud Misthress O'Gill would have flung back in answer no one knows, bekase whin once purvoked she has few ayquils for sarcastic langwidge, but just then Elizabeth Ann put in Bridget's hand a steaming cup of good, sthrong tay. Now, whusky, ale, an' porther are all good enough in their places, yer honour—I've nothing to intimidate aginst them—but for a comforting, soothering, edayfing buverage give me a cup of foine black tay. So this day the cups were filled only the second time, when the subject of husbands was complately dhropped, an' the conwersation wandhered to the misdaymeanours of Anthony Sullivan's goat.

All this time the women had been so busy with their talkin' an' argyfyin' that the creeping darkness of a coming storm had stolen unnoticed into the room, making the fire glow brighter and redder on the hearth. A faint flare of lightning, follyed be a low grumble of thunder, brought the women to their feet.

"Marcy on us!" says Caycelia Crow, glad of an excuse to be gone,"do you hear that? We'll all be dhrownded before we raich home," says she.

In a minute the wisitors, afther dhraining their cups, were out in the road, aich hurryin' on her separate way, an' tying her bonnet-sthrings as she wint. 'Twas a heavy an' a guilty heart that Bridget carried home with her through the gathering storm. Although Darby was a nuntimate friend of the fairies, yet, as Margit Doyle said, he had such a black dhread of all other kinds of ghosts that to get him out on this threatening Halloween night, to walk past the churchyard, as he must do on his way to Cormac McCarthy's cottage, was a job ayquil to liftin' the Shannon bridge. How she was to manage it she couldn't for the life of her tell; but if the errant was left undone she would be the laughin'-stock of every woman in the parish.

But worst of all, an' what cut her heart the sorest, was that she had turned an act of neighbourly kindness into a wainglorious boast; an' that, she doubted not, was a mortal sin.

She had promised Cormac in the afthernoon that as soon as she got home she would send Darby over with some tay for poor little Eileen, an' now a big storm was gathering, an' before she could have supper ready, thry as hard as she could, black night might be upon them.

"To bring aise to the dying is the comfortingist privilege a man or woman can have, an' I've thraded it for a miserable settin' of eggs," she says. "Amn't I the unfortunit crachure," she thought, "to have let me pride rune me this away. What'll I do at all at all?" she cried. "Bad luck to the thought that took me out of me way to Elizabeth Egan's house!"

Then she med a wish that she might be able to get home in time to send Darby on his errant before the night came on. "If they laugh at me, that'll be my punishment, an' maybe it'll clane my sin," says she.

But the wish was in wain. For just as she crossed the stile to her own field the sun dhropped behind the hills as though he had been shot, an' the east wind swept up, carrying with it a sky full of black clouds an' rain.

II

That same All Sowls' night Darby O'Gill, the friend of the fairies, sat, as he had often sat before, amidst the dancin' shadows, ferninst his own crackling turf and wood fire, listening to the storm beat against his cottage windows. Little Mickey, his six-year-ould, cuddled asleep on his daddy's lap, whilst Bridget sat beside thim, the other childher cruedled around her. My, oh my, how the rain powered and hammered an' swirled!

Out in the highway the big dhrops smashed agin wayfarers' faces like blows from a fist, and once in a while, over the flooded moors and the far row of lonesome hills, the sullen lightning spurted red and angry, like the wicious flare of a wolcano.

You may well say 'twas perfect weather for Halloween—to-night whin the spirits of the dayparted dead visit once again their homes, and sit unseen, listening an' yearnin' about the ould hearthstones.

More than once that avenin' Darby'd shivered and shuddered at the wild shrieks and wails that swept over the chimney-tops; he bein' sartin sure that it wasn't the wind at all, but despairing woices that cried out to him from the could lips of the dead.

At last, afther one purticular doleful cry that rose and fell and lingered around the roof, the knowledgeable man raised his head and fetched a deep breath, and said to his wife Bridget:

"Do you hear that cry, avourneen? The dear Lord be marciful to the souls of the dayparted!" sighed he.

Bridget turned a throubled face toward him. "Amen," she says, speakin' softly; "and may He presarve them who are dying this night. Poor Eileen McCarthy an' she the purty, light-footed colleen only married the few months! Haven't we the raysons to be thankful and grateful. We can never pray enough, Darby," says she.

Now the family had just got off their knees from night prayers, that had lasted half an hour, so thim last worruds worried Darby greatly.

"That woman," he says to himself, mighty sour, "is this minute contimplaytin' an' insinuatin' that we haven't said prayers enough for Eileen, when as it is, me two poor knees have blisters on thim as big as hin's eggs from kneelin'. An' if I don't lookout," he says to himself again, "she'll put the childher to bed and then she's down on her knees for another hour, and me wid her; I'd never advise anyone to marry such a pious woman. I'm fairly kilt with rayligion, so I am. I must disthract her mind an' prevent her intintions," he says to himself.

"Maybe, Bridget," he says, out loud, as he was readying his pipe, "it ain't so bad afther all for Eileen. If we keep hoping for the best, we'll chate the worst out of a few good hours at any rate," says the knowledgeable man.

But Bridget only rowled the apron about her folded arms and shook her head sorrowful at the fire. Darby squinted carefully down the stem of his pipe, blew in it, took a sly glance at his wife, and wint on:

"Don't you raymember, Bridget," he says, "whin ould Mrs. Rafferty lay sick of a bad informaytion of the stomick; well, the banshee sat for a full hour keening an' cryin' before their house just as it did last night outside Cormac McCarthy's. An' you know the banshee cried but once at Rafferty's, but never rayturned the second time. The informaytion left Julia, and all the wide worruld knows, even the King of Spain might know if he'd send to ax, that Julia Rafferty, as strong as a horse, was diggin' petaties in her own field as late as yesterday."

"The banshee comes three nights before anyone dies, doesn't it, daddy?" says little Mickey, waking up, all excited.

"It does that," says Darby, smilin' proud at the child's knowledgeableness; "and it's come but once to Eileen McCarthy."

"An' while the banshee cries, she sits combing her hair with a comb of goold, don't she, daddy?"

Bridget sat onaisy, bitin' her lips. Always an' ever she had sthrove to keep from the childher tidings of fairies and of banshees an' ghosts an' other onnatural people. Twice she trun a warning look at Darby, but he, not noticin', wint on, strokin' the little lad's hair, an' sayin' to him:

"It does, indade, avick; an' as she came but once to Mrs. Rafferty's, so we have rayson to hope she'll come no more to Cormac McCarthy's."

"Hush that nonsinse!" says Bridget, lookin' daggers; "sure Jack Doolan says that 't was no banshee at all that come to Rafferty's, but only himself who had taken a drop too much at the fair, an' on his way home sat down to rest himself by Rafferty's door. He says that he stharted singin' pious hymns to kape off the evil spirits, and everyone knows that the same Jack Doolan has as turrible a woice for singin' as any banshee that ever twishted a lip," she says.

The woman's conthrayriness vexed Darby so he pounded his knee with his fist as he answered her: "You'll not deny, maybe," he says, "that the Costa Bower sthopped one night at the Hall, and——"

"Whist!" cried Bridget "lave off," she says; "sure that's no kind of talk to be talkin' this night before the childher," says she.

"But mammy, I know what the Costa Bower is," cried little Mickey, sitting up straight in Darby's lap an' pinting his finger at his mother; "'tis I that knows well. The Costa Bower is a gr-r-reat black coach that comes in the night to carry down to Croagmah the dead people the banshee keened for."

The other childher by now were sitting boult upright, stiff as ramrods, and staring wild-eyed at Mickey.

"The coachman's head is cut off an' he houlds the reins this away," says the child, lettin' his hands fall limp an' open at his side. "Sometimes it's all wisable, an' then agin it's unwisable, but always whin it comes one can hear the turrible rumble of its wheels." Mickey's woice fell and, spreading out his hands, he spoke slow an' solemn. "One Halloween night in the woods down at the black pond, Danny Hogan heard it coming an' he jumped behind a stone. The threes couldn't sthop it, they wint right through it, an' as it passed Danny Hogan says he saw one white, dead face laned back agin the dark cushions, an' this is the night—All Sowls' night—whin it's sure to be out; now don't I know?" he says, thriumphant.

At that Bridget started to her feet. For a minute she stood spacheless with vexation at the wild, frighting notions that had got into the heads of her childher; then "Glory be!" she says, looking hard at Darby. You could have heard a pin dhrop in the room. Ould Malachi, the big yellow cat, who until this time lay coiled asleep on a stool, was the best judge of Bridget's charackter in that house. So, no sooner did he hear the worruds an' see Bridget start up, than he was on his own four feet, his back arched, his tail straight up, an' his two goolden eyes searchin' her face. One look was enough for him. The next instant he lept to the ground an' started for the far room. As he scampered through the door, he trew a swift look back at his comerades, the childher, an' that look said plain as any worruds could say:

"Run for it while you've time! Folly me; some one of us vagebones has done something murtherin'!"

Malachi was right; there would have been sayrious throuble for all hands, only that a softening thought was on Bridget that night which sobered her temper. She stopped a bit, the frown on her face clearing as she looked at the childher, an' she only said: "Come out of this! To bed with yez! I'm raising a pack of owdacious young romancers, an' I didn't know it. Mickey sthop that whimpering an' make haste with your clothes. The Lord help us, he's broke off another button. Look at that, now!" she says.

There was no help for thim. So, with longin' looks trun back at their father, sittin' cosey before the fire, an' with consolin' winks an' nods from him, the childher followed their mother to the bedroom.

Thin, whilst Bridget was tucking the covers about them, an' hushing their complainings, Darby sat with his elbows on his knees, doing in his head a sum in figures; an' that sum was this:

"How much would it be worth this All Sowls' night for a man to go out that door and walk past the churchyard up to Cormac McCarthy, the stone-cutter's house?" One time he made the answer as low as tin pounds two shillings and thruppence, but as he did so a purticular loud blast went shrieking past outside, an' he raised the answer to one thousand five hundred an' tunty pounds sterling. "And cheap at that," he said aloud.

While he was studyin' thim saygacious questions, Bridget stole quietly behind and put a light hand on his chowlder. For a minute, thin, nayther of thim said a worrud.

Surprised at the silence, an' puzzled that little Mickey had escaped a larruping, Malachi crept from the far room an' stood still in the doorway judging his misthress. An' expression was on her face the cat couldn't quite make out. 'Twas an elevayted, pitying, good-hearted, daytermined look, such as a man wears when he goes into the sty to kill one of his own pigs for Christmas.

Malachi, being a wise an' expayieranced baste, daycided to take no chances, so he backed through the door again an' hid undher the dhresser to listen.

"I was just thinking, Darby avourneen," says the woman, half whuspering, "how we might this blessed night earn great credit for our two sowls."

"Wait!" says the sly man, straightening himself, an' raising a hand. "The very thing you're going to spake was in my own mind. I was just dayliberatin' that I hadn't done justice to-night to poor Eileen. I haven't said me prayers farvint enough. I niver can whin we're praying together, or whin I'm kneeling down. Thin, like every way else, there's something quare about me. The foinest prayers I ever say is whin I'm be myself alone in the fields," says the conniving villyan. "So, do you, Bridget, go in an' kneel down by the childher for a half hour or so, an' I'll sit here doing my best. If you should happen to look out at me ye might aisily think," he says, "that I was only sittin' here comfortably smoking my pipe, but at the same time prayers'll be whirlin' inside of me like a wind-mill," says he.

"Oh, thin, ain't I glad an' happy to hear you say thim worruds," says his wife, puttin' one foine arrum about his neck; "you've taken a load off my heart that's been weighing heavy on it all night, for I thought maybe you'd be afeard."

"Afeard of what?" axed Darby, liftin' his eyebrows. Malachi throtted bouldly in an' jumped up on the stool.

"You know Father Cassidy says," whuspered Bridget, "that a loving deed of the hands done for the disthressed is itself a prayer worth a week of common prayers."

"I have nothin' agin that sayin'," says Darby, his head cocked, an' he growin' suspicious.

Bridget wiped her forehead with her apron. "Well, this afthernoon I was at McCarthy's house,"' she wint on, soothering his hair with one hand, "an', oh, but the poor child was disthressed! Her cheeks were flaming with the faver. An', Darby, the thirst, the awful thirst! I looked about for a pinch of tay—there's nothing so coolin' for one in the faver as a cup of wake tay—an' the sorra scrap of it was in the house, so I tould Cormac that to-night, as soon as the childher were in bed, I'd send you over with a pinch."

Every one of Darby's four bones stiffened an' a mortial chill sthruck into his heart.

"Listen, darlint," she says, "the storm's dying down, so while you're putting on your greatcoat I'll wrap up the bit of tay." He shook her hand from his chowldhers.

"Woman," he says, with bitther politeness, "I think you said that we had a great chanst to get credit for our two sowls. That's what I think you raymarked and stibulated," says he.

"Arrah, shouldn't a woman have great praise an' credit who'll send her husband out on such a night as this," his wife says. "The worse the conditions, the more credit she'll get. If a ghost were to jump at ye as you go past the churchyard, oughtn't I be the happy woman entirely?" says Bridget.

There was a kind of a tinkle in her woice, such as comes when Bridget is telling jokes, so Darby, with a sudden hope in his mind, turned quick to look at her. But there she stood grim, unfeeling, an' daytermined as a pinted gun.

"Oh, ho! is that the way it is?" he says. "Well, here's luck an' good fortune to the ghost or skelling-ton that lays his hand on me this blessed night!" He stuck his two hands deep in his pockets and whirled one leg across the other—the most aggrawating thing a man can do. But Bridget was not the laste discouraged; she only made up her mind to come at him on his soft side, so she spoke up an' said:

"Suppose I was dying of the faver, Darby O'Gill, an' Cormac rayfused to bring over a pinch of tay to me. What, then, would ye think of the stone-cutter?"

Malachi, the cat, stopped licking his paws, an' trun a sharp, inquiring eye at his master.

"Bridget," says the knowledgeable man, giving his hand an argifying wave. "We have two separate ways of being good. Your way is to scurry round an' do good acts. My way is to keep from doing bad ones. An' who knows," he says, with a pious sigh, "which way is the betther one. It isn't for us to judge," says he, shakin' his head solemn at the fire.

Bridget walked out in front of him an' fowlded her arms tight.

"So you won't go," she says, sharp an' suddin'.

"The divil a foot!" says he, beginnin' to whustle.

You'd think, now, Bridget was bate, but she still hildt her trump card, an' until that was played an' lost the lad wasn't safe. "All right, me brave hayro," says she; "do you sit there be the fire; I'll go meself," she says. With that she bounced into the childher's room an' began to get ready her cloak an' hood.

For a minute Darby sat pokin' the fire, muttherin' to himself an' feeling very discommodious. Thin, just to show he wasn't the laste bit onaisy, the lad cleared his throat, and waggin' his head at the fire, began to sing:
<blockquote>"Yarra! as I walked out one mor-r-ning' all in the month of June
The primrosies and daisies an' cowslips were in bloom,
I spied a purty fair maid a-sthrollin' on the lea,
An' Rory Bory Alice, nor any other ould ancient haythan goddess
was not half so fair as she.
Says I, 'Me purty fair maid, l'll take you for me bride,
An' if you'll pay no at-TIN-tion——'"</blockquote>
Glancing up sudden, he saw Malachi's eye on him, and if ever the faytures of a cat spoke silent but plain langwidge Malachi's face talked that minute to its master, and this is what it said:

"Well, of all the cowardly, creaking bostheens I ever see in all me born days you are the worst, Darby O'Gill. You've not only guve impidence to your wife—an' she's worth four of you—but you've gone back on the friends you purtended to——"

Malachi's faytures got no further in their insultin' raymarks, for at that Darby swooped up a big sod of turf an' let it fly at the owdacious baste.

Now it is well known that be a spontaneous trow like that no one ever yet hit a sinsible cat, but always an' ever in that unlucky endayvour he strikes a damaginger blow where it's not intinded. So it was this time.

Bridget, wearing her red cloak an' hood, was just coming through the door, an' that misfortunate sod of turf caught her fair an' square, right below the chist, an' she staggered back agin the wall.

Darby's consthernaytion an' complycation an' turpitaytion were beyant imaginaytion.

Bridget laned there gasping. If she felt as bad as she looked, four Dublint surgunts with their saws an' knives couldn't have done her a ha-porth of good. Howsumever, for all that, the sly woman had seen Malachi dodge an' go gallopin' away, but she purtendid to think 'twas at herself the turf was trun. Not that she scolded, or anything so common as that, but she went on like an early Christian marthyer who was just goin' to be inthrojuiced to the roaring loins.

Well, as you may aisy see, the poor man, her husband, hadn't a chanst in the worruld afther that. Of course, to rightify himself, he'd face all the ghosts in Croaghmah. So, in a minute, he was standing in his greatcoat with his hand on the latch. There was a packet of tay in his pocket, an' he was a subdued an' conquered man.

He looked so woful that Bridget raypented an' almost raylinted.

"Raymember," he says, mournful, "if I'm caught this night be the Costa Bower, or be the banshee, take good care of the childher, an' raymember what I say—I didn't mane, Bridget, to hit ye with that sod of turf."

"Oh, ain't ye the foolish darlin' to be afeared," smiled Bridget back at him, but she was sayrious, too. "Don't you know that when one goes on an errant of marcy a score of God's white angels with swoords in their hands march before an' beside an' afther him, keeping his path free from danger?" With that she pulled his face down to hers, an' kissed him as she used in the ould courtin' days.

There's nothing puts so much high courage an' clear, steadfast purpose in a man's heart, if it be properly given, as a kiss from the woman he loves. So, with the warmth of that kiss to cheer him, Darby set his face agin the storm.]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>531</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date><![CDATA[2019-08-20 17:27:27]]></wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt><![CDATA[2019-08-20 21:27:27]]></wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status><![CDATA[closed]]></wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status><![CDATA[closed]]></wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name><![CDATA[the-banshees-comb-chapter-1]]></wp:post_name>
		<wp:status><![CDATA[publish]]></wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type><![CDATA[story]]></wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password><![CDATA[]]></wp:post_password>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
										<category domain="demon" nicename="banshee"><![CDATA[Banshee]]></category>
		<category domain="demon" nicename="coiste-bodhar"><![CDATA[Cóiste Bodhar]]></category>
		<category domain="theme" nicename="confrontation-with-death"><![CDATA[confrontation with death]]></category>
		<category domain="author" nicename="herminie-templeton-kavanagh"><![CDATA[Herminie Templeton Kavanagh]]></category>
		<category domain="theme" nicename="human-brotherhood"><![CDATA[human brotherhood]]></category>
		<category domain="region" nicename="154"><![CDATA[Northern Europe]]></category>
		<category domain="theme" nicename="triumph-by-trickery"><![CDATA[triumph by trickery]]></category>
						<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_edit_last]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[67389914]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							</item>
					<item>
		<title>The Ankou (and other tales)</title>
		<link>https://shortandsweet.wtf/story/the-ankou-and-other-tales/</link>
		<pubDate>Tue, 20 Aug 2019 21:34:26 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[eegering]]></dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://shortandsweet.wtf/?post_type=story&#038;p=533</guid>
		<description></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[Death is personified in Lower Brittany by the Ankou, who travels about the country in a cart picking up souls. At night a wain is heard coming along the road with a creaking axle. It halts at a door, and that is the summons. A spirit passes, and the Ankou moves on.

<!--more-->

A curious story is told by an old Byzantine writer concerning the western coast of Finistère. He says that at night a boat lies attached to the shore, and the boatman hears himself called. He goes forth and takes his oars. Then he hears a stirring, and gradually his bark becomes laden, but nothing is seen. When the boat is so charged that it nearly touches the water's edge he puts forth and rows to one of the islands off the coast, whereat those who are invisible step forth, and his vessel is lightened; and so he returns to the mainland. He has ferried the dead across to the islands in the stormy Atlantic which are the permanent habitation of the souls of the departed.

The great Islands of the Dead were doubtless Ouessant, and Sein, off the Bay des Trépassés in Cornouaille. This latter island in pagan times was occupied by nine virgins who were consulted as oracles, and who were credited with the power of raising or laying storms. None might consult them who were not sailors. Probably with them, as with another college of priestesses in an island in the Loire, it was an obligation on a certain day to pull down and reconstruct the roof of their temple. If by chance one of them let fall any sacred object, any portion of the thatch, her companions rushed on her with hideous cries, tore her limb from limb, and then scattered her blood-stained flesh about the island.]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>533</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date><![CDATA[2019-08-20 17:34:26]]></wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt><![CDATA[2019-08-20 21:34:26]]></wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status><![CDATA[closed]]></wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status><![CDATA[closed]]></wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name><![CDATA[the-ankou-and-other-tales]]></wp:post_name>
		<wp:status><![CDATA[publish]]></wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type><![CDATA[story]]></wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password><![CDATA[]]></wp:post_password>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
										<category domain="demon" nicename="ankou"><![CDATA[Ankou]]></category>
		<category domain="theme" nicename="confrontation-with-death"><![CDATA[confrontation with death]]></category>
		<category domain="theme" nicename="isolation"><![CDATA[isolation]]></category>
		<category domain="author" nicename="sabine-baring-gould"><![CDATA[Sabine Baring-Gould]]></category>
		<category domain="theme" nicename="the-mysterious-stranger"><![CDATA[the mysterious stranger]]></category>
		<category domain="region" nicename="155"><![CDATA[Western Europe]]></category>
		<category domain="theme" nicename="woman-in-a-male-society"><![CDATA[woman in a male society]]></category>
						<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_edit_last]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[67389914]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							</item>
				</channel>
</rss>
	